// Class id is ID of class

final data = {
  "Kips": {
    "EXAM_CHAPTER": [
      {"ID": "1", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "1", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "2", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "1", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "4", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "1", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "5", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "2", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "6", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "2", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "7", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "2", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "8", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "3", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "9", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "3", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "10", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "3", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "11", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "4", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "12", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "4", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "13", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "4", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "14", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "5", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "15", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "5", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "16", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "5", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "17", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "6", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "18", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "6", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "19", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "6", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "20", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "7", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "21", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "7", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "22", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "7", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "23", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "8", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "24", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "8", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "25", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "8", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "26", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "9", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "27", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "9", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "28", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "9", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "29", "NAME": "Exam-1", "CLASSID": "10", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "30", "NAME": "Exam-2", "CLASSID": "10", "TIME": "20"},
      {"ID": "31", "NAME": "Exam-3", "CLASSID": "10", "TIME": "20"}
    ],
    "EXAM_QUESTION_MASTER": [
      {
        "ID": "1",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "2",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "3",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "4",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "5",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "8",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "9",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "12",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "13",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "14",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "16",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "18",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "19",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "20",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "21",
        "QUESTION": "What does a computer need to work with?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Data",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "23",
        "QUESTION": "Where does a computer store data?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Memory",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "24",
        "QUESTION": "Does a computer forget the data stored in it?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "No",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "25",
        "QUESTION": "Does a computer make any mistake?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "No",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "28",
        "QUESTION": "What are the letters or numbers in a computer known as?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "29",
        "QUESTION":
            "Can a computer recall the data which is stored in its memory?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "30",
        "QUESTION": "Information written in words and numbers is called data.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "31",
        "QUESTION": "A computer cannot store a lot of data.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "32",
        "QUESTION": "Data can be words,numbers or pictures.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "33",
        "QUESTION": "A computer cannot store numbers.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "34",
        "QUESTION": "AATD",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "6",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "35",
        "QUESTION": "YRMOEM",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "6",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "36",
        "QUESTION": "DWRO",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "6",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "37",
        "QUESTION": "BRDOYKEA",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "6",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "38",
        "QUESTION": "MRBNUE",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "6",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "39",
        "QUESTION": "What does a computer store?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Information",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "40",
        "QUESTION": "How much time does a computer take to calculate?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Seconds",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "42",
        "QUESTION": "A computer can solve sums.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "43",
        "QUESTION": "A computer can do cleaning.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "44",
        "QUESTION": "A computer can do your homework.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "46",
        "QUESTION": "A computer is a useless machine.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "47",
        "QUESTION": "A computer cannot store any information.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "48",
        "QUESTION": "We can use computer for our studies.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "49",
        "QUESTION": "We cannot draw pictures on a computer",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "50",
        "QUESTION": "We can watch cartoons on a computer",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "51",
        "QUESTION": "We can hear only English songs on a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "52",
        "QUESTION": "We can play........on a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Games",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "53",
        "QUESTION": "We can write........on a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Letters",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "54",
        "QUESTION": "We can listen......on a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Music",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "56",
        "QUESTION": "We can draw......on a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Pictures",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "57",
        "QUESTION": "We can watch......on a computer",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Movies",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "58",
        "QUESTION": "A computer never gets.......",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Tired",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "59",
        "QUESTION": "What does a computer do?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Saves our time",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "60",
        "QUESTION": "Which works faster",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Computer",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "61",
        "QUESTION": "CO_PU_ER",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "62",
        "QUESTION": "K_YB_ _RD",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "63",
        "QUESTION": "M_NI_ _R",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "64",
        "QUESTION": "M_U_E",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "65",
        "QUESTION": "ST_R_G_",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "66",
        "QUESTION": "M_ _H_NE",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "67",
        "QUESTION": "O_TP_ _",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "68",
        "QUESTION": "G_M_S",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "69",
        "QUESTION": "I_P_T",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "70",
        "QUESTION": "D_T_A",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "71",
        "QUESTION": "M_MO_Y",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "72",
        "QUESTION": "F_OP_Y",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "73",
        "QUESTION": "E_T_ _",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "74",
        "QUESTION": "T_L_V_S_ _N",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "75",
        "QUESTION": "B_ _TO_S",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "76",
        "QUESTION": "K_ _",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "77",
        "QUESTION": "C_RS_ _",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "79",
        "QUESTION": "D_ _ET_",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "80",
        "QUESTION": "CL_ _ K_ _G",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "81",
        "QUESTION": "SH_FT",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "82",
        "QUESTION": "SP_ _E_ _R",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "83",
        "QUESTION": "B_ _ K_P_ _E",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "84",
        "QUESTION": "C_ _SL_C_",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "86",
        "QUESTION": "D_SK_ _P",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "87",
        "QUESTION": "P_I_T",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "88",
        "QUESTION": "P_O_R_ _",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "89",
        "QUESTION": "_O_LB_ _",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "90",
        "QUESTION": "_ _C_ _R_",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "91",
        "QUESTION": "D_ _W_NG",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "92",
        "QUESTION": "E_ _IP_E",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "7",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "93",
        "QUESTION": "CPU",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CENTRAL PROCESSING UNIT",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "3",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "15"
      },
      {
        "ID": "94",
        "QUESTION": "VDU",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "VISUAL DISPLAY UNIT",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "3",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "10"
      },
      {
        "ID": "95",
        "QUESTION": "CD",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "COMPACT DISK",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "3",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "16"
      },
      {
        "ID": "96",
        "QUESTION": "MU",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "MEMORY UNIT",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "3",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "20"
      },
      {
        "ID": "97",
        "QUESTION": "CU",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CONTROL UNIT",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "3",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "17"
      },
      {
        "ID": "98",
        "QUESTION": "ALU",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "ARITHMETIC AND LOGICAL UNIT",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "3",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "15"
      },
      {
        "ID": "99",
        "QUESTION": "TV",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "TELEVISION",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "3",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "15"
      },
      {
        "ID": "100",
        "QUESTION": "UPS",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "UN-INTERRUPTED POWER SUPPLY",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "3",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "19"
      },
      {
        "ID": "101",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "102",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "103",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "104",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "105",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "106",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "107",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "108",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "109",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "110",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "111",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "112",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "113",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "114",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "115",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "116",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "117",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "118",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "119",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "120",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "121",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "122",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "123",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "124",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "125",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "126",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "127",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "128",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "129",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "130",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "131",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "132",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "133",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "134",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "135",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "136",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "137",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "138",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "139",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "140",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "141",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "142",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "143",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "144",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "145",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "146",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "147",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "148",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "149",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "150",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "151",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "152",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "153",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "154",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "155",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "156",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "157",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "158",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "159",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "160",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "161",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "162",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "163",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "164",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "165",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "166",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "167",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "168",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "169",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "170",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "171",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "172",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "173",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "174",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "175",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "176",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "177",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "178",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "179",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "180",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "181",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "182",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "183",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "184",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "185",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "186",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "187",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "188",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "189",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "190",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "191",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "192",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "193",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "194",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "195",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "196",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "197",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "198",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "199",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "200",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "201",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "202",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "203",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "204",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "205",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "206",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "207",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "208",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "209",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "210",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "211",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "212",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "213",
        "QUESTION": "Which is the longest key on a keyboard?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "214",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to type the letters in capital?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CapsLock",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "215",
        "QUESTION": "What do we call a small blinking line on the monitor?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "216",
        "QUESTION": "Which key brings the cursor to the next line?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "217",
        "QUESTION": "Which key is used to give blank space between the words?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "218",
        "QUESTION": "How many Caps Lock keys are there on a keyboard?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "219",
        "QUESTION": "Which key looks like a corner?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "220",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key is pressed to type the sentence in different lines?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "221",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key is used to give spaces between letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "222",
        "QUESTION": "Enter key brings the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "223",
        "QUESTION": "Cursor is the small blinking line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "224",
        "QUESTION": "Caps lock key looks like a corner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "225",
        "QUESTION": "Spacebar is the longest key on the keyboard",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "226",
        "QUESTION": "Caps Lock key is used to write in capital letters.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      }
    ],
    "EXAM_OPTION_MASTER": [
      {"ID": "1", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "1"},
      {"ID": "2", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "1"},
      {"ID": "3", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "1"},
      {"ID": "4", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "1"},
      {"ID": "5", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "2"},
      {"ID": "6", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "2"},
      {"ID": "7", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "2"},
      {"ID": "8", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "2"},
      {"ID": "9", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "3"},
      {"ID": "10", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "3"},
      {"ID": "11", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "3"},
      {"ID": "12", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "3"},
      {"ID": "13", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "4"},
      {"ID": "14", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "4"},
      {"ID": "15", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "4"},
      {"ID": "16", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "4"},
      {"ID": "17", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "5"},
      {"ID": "18", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "5"},
      {"ID": "19", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "5"},
      {"ID": "20", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "5"},
      {"ID": "23", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "8"},
      {"ID": "29", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "9"},
      {"ID": "32", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "12"},
      {"ID": "35", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "13"},
      {"ID": "36", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "13"},
      {"ID": "37", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "14"},
      {"ID": "38", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "14"},
      {"ID": "39", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "16"},
      {"ID": "40", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "16"},
      {"ID": "41", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "18"},
      {"ID": "42", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "18"},
      {"ID": "43", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "19"},
      {"ID": "44", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "19"},
      {"ID": "45", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "20"},
      {"ID": "46", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "20"},
      {"ID": "47", "OPTION": "Information", "QUESTIONID": "21"},
      {"ID": "48", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "21"},
      {"ID": "49", "OPTION": "Picture", "QUESTIONID": "21"},
      {"ID": "50", "OPTION": "None", "QUESTIONID": "21"},
      {"ID": "51", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "23"},
      {"ID": "52", "OPTION": "Disk", "QUESTIONID": "23"},
      {"ID": "53", "OPTION": "Memory", "QUESTIONID": "23"},
      {"ID": "54", "OPTION": "Number", "QUESTIONID": "23"},
      {"ID": "55", "OPTION": "Yes", "QUESTIONID": "24"},
      {"ID": "56", "OPTION": "No", "QUESTIONID": "24"},
      {"ID": "57", "OPTION": "No", "QUESTIONID": "25"},
      {"ID": "58", "OPTION": "Yes", "QUESTIONID": "25"},
      {"ID": "59", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "28"},
      {"ID": "60", "OPTION": "Yes", "QUESTIONID": "29"},
      {"ID": "61", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "30"},
      {"ID": "62", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "30"},
      {"ID": "63", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "31"},
      {"ID": "64", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "31"},
      {"ID": "65", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "32"},
      {"ID": "66", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "32"},
      {"ID": "67", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "33"},
      {"ID": "68", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "33"},
      {"ID": "69", "OPTION": "DATA", "QUESTIONID": "34"},
      {"ID": "70", "OPTION": "MEMORY", "QUESTIONID": "35"},
      {"ID": "71", "OPTION": "WORD", "QUESTIONID": "36"},
      {"ID": "72", "OPTION": "KEYBOARD", "QUESTIONID": "37"},
      {"ID": "73", "OPTION": "NUMBER", "QUESTIONID": "38"},
      {"ID": "74", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "39"},
      {"ID": "75", "OPTION": "Picture", "QUESTIONID": "39"},
      {"ID": "76", "OPTION": "Number", "QUESTIONID": "39"},
      {"ID": "77", "OPTION": "Information", "QUESTIONID": "39"},
      {"ID": "78", "OPTION": "Minutes", "QUESTIONID": "40"},
      {"ID": "79", "OPTION": "Hours", "QUESTIONID": "40"},
      {"ID": "80", "OPTION": "Days", "QUESTIONID": "40"},
      {"ID": "81", "OPTION": "Seconds", "QUESTIONID": "40"},
      {"ID": "82", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "42"},
      {"ID": "83", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "42"},
      {"ID": "84", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "43"},
      {"ID": "85", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "43"},
      {"ID": "86", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "44"},
      {"ID": "87", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "44"},
      {"ID": "89", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "46"},
      {"ID": "90", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "46"},
      {"ID": "91", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "47"},
      {"ID": "92", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "47"},
      {"ID": "93", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "48"},
      {"ID": "94", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "48"},
      {"ID": "95", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "49"},
      {"ID": "96", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "49"},
      {"ID": "97", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "50"},
      {"ID": "98", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "50"},
      {"ID": "99", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "51"},
      {"ID": "100", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "51"},
      {"ID": "101", "OPTION": "Letter", "QUESTIONID": "52"},
      {"ID": "102", "OPTION": "Text", "QUESTIONID": "52"},
      {"ID": "103", "OPTION": "Games", "QUESTIONID": "52"},
      {"ID": "104", "OPTION": "Games", "QUESTIONID": "53"},
      {"ID": "105", "OPTION": "Letters", "QUESTIONID": "53"},
      {"ID": "106", "OPTION": "Pictures", "QUESTIONID": "53"},
      {"ID": "107", "OPTION": "Movies", "QUESTIONID": "54"},
      {"ID": "108", "OPTION": "Music", "QUESTIONID": "54"},
      {"ID": "109", "OPTION": "Games", "QUESTIONID": "54"},
      {"ID": "111", "OPTION": "Pictures", "QUESTIONID": "56"},
      {"ID": "112", "OPTION": "Games", "QUESTIONID": "56"},
      {"ID": "113", "OPTION": "Letters", "QUESTIONID": "56"},
      {"ID": "114", "OPTION": "Pictures", "QUESTIONID": "57"},
      {"ID": "115", "OPTION": "Movies", "QUESTIONID": "57"},
      {"ID": "116", "OPTION": "Sums", "QUESTIONID": "57"},
      {"ID": "117", "OPTION": "Tired", "QUESTIONID": "58"},
      {"ID": "118", "OPTION": "Hungry", "QUESTIONID": "58"},
      {"ID": "119", "OPTION": "Cupboard", "QUESTIONID": "58"},
      {"ID": "120", "OPTION": "Wastes our time", "QUESTIONID": "59"},
      {"ID": "121", "OPTION": "Saves our time", "QUESTIONID": "59"},
      {"ID": "122", "OPTION": "Run with time", "QUESTIONID": "59"},
      {"ID": "123", "OPTION": "Man", "QUESTIONID": "60"},
      {"ID": "124", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "60"},
      {"ID": "125", "OPTION": "Animals", "QUESTIONID": "60"},
      {"ID": "126", "OPTION": "COMPUTER", "QUESTIONID": "61"},
      {"ID": "127", "OPTION": "KEYBOARD", "QUESTIONID": "62"},
      {"ID": "128", "OPTION": "MONITOR", "QUESTIONID": "63"},
      {"ID": "129", "OPTION": "MOUSE", "QUESTIONID": "64"},
      {"ID": "130", "OPTION": "STORAGE", "QUESTIONID": "65"},
      {"ID": "131", "OPTION": "MACHINE", "QUESTIONID": "66"},
      {"ID": "132", "OPTION": "OUTPUT", "QUESTIONID": "67"},
      {"ID": "133", "OPTION": "GAMES", "QUESTIONID": "68"},
      {"ID": "134", "OPTION": "INPUT", "QUESTIONID": "69"},
      {"ID": "135", "OPTION": "DATA", "QUESTIONID": "70"},
      {"ID": "136", "OPTION": "MEMORY", "QUESTIONID": "71"},
      {"ID": "137", "OPTION": "FLOPPY", "QUESTIONID": "72"},
      {"ID": "138", "OPTION": "ENTER", "QUESTIONID": "73"},
      {"ID": "139", "OPTION": "TELEVISION", "QUESTIONID": "74"},
      {"ID": "140", "OPTION": "BUTTONS", "QUESTIONID": "75"},
      {"ID": "141", "OPTION": "KEY", "QUESTIONID": "76"},
      {"ID": "142", "OPTION": "CURSOR", "QUESTIONID": "77"},
      {"ID": "144", "OPTION": "DELETE", "QUESTIONID": "79"},
      {"ID": "145", "OPTION": "CLICKING", "QUESTIONID": "80"},
      {"ID": "146", "OPTION": "SHIFT", "QUESTIONID": "81"},
      {"ID": "147", "OPTION": "SPACEBAR", "QUESTIONID": "82"},
      {"ID": "148", "OPTION": "BACKSPACE", "QUESTIONID": "83"},
      {"ID": "149", "OPTION": "CAPSLOCK", "QUESTIONID": "84"},
      {"ID": "151", "OPTION": "DESKTOP", "QUESTIONID": "86"},
      {"ID": "152", "OPTION": "PAINT", "QUESTIONID": "87"},
      {"ID": "153", "OPTION": "PROGRAM", "QUESTIONID": "88"},
      {"ID": "154", "OPTION": "TOOLBOX", "QUESTIONID": "89"},
      {"ID": "155", "OPTION": "PICTURE", "QUESTIONID": "90"},
      {"ID": "156", "OPTION": "DRAWING", "QUESTIONID": "91"},
      {"ID": "157", "OPTION": "ELLIPSE", "QUESTIONID": "92"},
      {"ID": "158", "OPTION": "CONTROL PROCESSING UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "93"},
      {"ID": "159", "OPTION": "CENTRAL PROCUDURE UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "93"},
      {"ID": "160", "OPTION": "CENTRAL PROCESS UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "93"},
      {"ID": "161", "OPTION": "CENTRAL PROCESSING UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "93"},
      {"ID": "162", "OPTION": "VISUAL DISPLAY UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "94"},
      {"ID": "163", "OPTION": "VITAL DISPLAY UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "94"},
      {"ID": "164", "OPTION": "VISUAL DEVICE UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "94"},
      {"ID": "165", "OPTION": "NONE", "QUESTIONID": "94"},
      {"ID": "166", "OPTION": "CONTROL DISK", "QUESTIONID": "95"},
      {"ID": "167", "OPTION": "COMPACT DEVICE", "QUESTIONID": "95"},
      {"ID": "168", "OPTION": "COMPACT DISK", "QUESTIONID": "95"},
      {"ID": "169", "OPTION": "CONTROL DEVICE", "QUESTIONID": "95"},
      {"ID": "170", "OPTION": "MEMORY UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "96"},
      {"ID": "171", "OPTION": "MEMBER UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "96"},
      {"ID": "172", "OPTION": "MORE UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "96"},
      {"ID": "173", "OPTION": "MOST UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "96"},
      {"ID": "174", "OPTION": "COMPACT UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "97"},
      {"ID": "175", "OPTION": "CONTROL UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "97"},
      {"ID": "176", "OPTION": "CENTRAL UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "97"},
      {"ID": "177", "OPTION": "NONE", "QUESTIONID": "97"},
      {
        "ID": "178",
        "OPTION": "ARITHMETIC AND LOGICAL UNIT",
        "QUESTIONID": "98"
      },
      {"ID": "179", "OPTION": "ARITHMETIC AND LOCAL UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "98"},
      {"ID": "180", "OPTION": "AND-OR LOGICAL UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "98"},
      {"ID": "181", "OPTION": "ARITHMETIC LOGICAL UNIT", "QUESTIONID": "98"},
      {"ID": "182", "OPTION": "TELESCOPE", "QUESTIONID": "99"},
      {"ID": "183", "OPTION": "TELEGRAPHY", "QUESTIONID": "99"},
      {"ID": "184", "OPTION": "TELEVISION", "QUESTIONID": "99"},
      {"ID": "185", "OPTION": "TELEPHONE", "QUESTIONID": "99"},
      {"ID": "186", "OPTION": "UNLIMITED POWER SUPPLY", "QUESTIONID": "100"},
      {"ID": "187", "OPTION": "UNIFORM POWER SUPPLY", "QUESTIONID": "100"},
      {
        "ID": "188",
        "OPTION": "UN-INTERRUPTED POWER SUPPLY",
        "QUESTIONID": "100"
      },
      {"ID": "189", "OPTION": "UN-OFF POWER SUPPLY", "QUESTIONID": "100"},
      {"ID": "190", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "101"},
      {"ID": "191", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "101"},
      {"ID": "192", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "101"},
      {"ID": "193", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "101"},
      {"ID": "194", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "102"},
      {"ID": "195", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "102"},
      {"ID": "196", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "102"},
      {"ID": "197", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "102"},
      {"ID": "198", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "103"},
      {"ID": "199", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "103"},
      {"ID": "200", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "103"},
      {"ID": "201", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "103"},
      {"ID": "202", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "104"},
      {"ID": "203", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "104"},
      {"ID": "204", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "104"},
      {"ID": "205", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "104"},
      {"ID": "206", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "105"},
      {"ID": "207", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "105"},
      {"ID": "208", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "105"},
      {"ID": "209", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "105"},
      {"ID": "210", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "106"},
      {"ID": "211", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "107"},
      {"ID": "212", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "108"},
      {"ID": "213", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "109"},
      {"ID": "214", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "109"},
      {"ID": "215", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "110"},
      {"ID": "216", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "110"},
      {"ID": "217", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "111"},
      {"ID": "218", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "111"},
      {"ID": "219", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "112"},
      {"ID": "220", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "112"},
      {"ID": "221", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "113"},
      {"ID": "222", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "113"},
      {"ID": "223", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "114"},
      {"ID": "224", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "114"},
      {"ID": "260", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "115"},
      {"ID": "261", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "115"},
      {"ID": "262", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "115"},
      {"ID": "263", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "115"},
      {"ID": "264", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "116"},
      {"ID": "265", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "116"},
      {"ID": "266", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "116"},
      {"ID": "267", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "116"},
      {"ID": "268", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "117"},
      {"ID": "269", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "117"},
      {"ID": "270", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "117"},
      {"ID": "271", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "117"},
      {"ID": "272", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "118"},
      {"ID": "273", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "118"},
      {"ID": "274", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "118"},
      {"ID": "275", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "118"},
      {"ID": "276", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "119"},
      {"ID": "277", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "119"},
      {"ID": "278", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "119"},
      {"ID": "279", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "119"},
      {"ID": "280", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "120"},
      {"ID": "281", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "121"},
      {"ID": "282", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "122"},
      {"ID": "283", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "123"},
      {"ID": "284", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "123"},
      {"ID": "285", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "124"},
      {"ID": "286", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "124"},
      {"ID": "287", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "125"},
      {"ID": "288", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "125"},
      {"ID": "289", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "126"},
      {"ID": "290", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "126"},
      {"ID": "291", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "127"},
      {"ID": "292", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "127"},
      {"ID": "293", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "128"},
      {"ID": "294", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "128"},
      {"ID": "295", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "129"},
      {"ID": "296", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "129"},
      {"ID": "297", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "129"},
      {"ID": "298", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "129"},
      {"ID": "299", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "130"},
      {"ID": "300", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "130"},
      {"ID": "301", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "130"},
      {"ID": "302", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "130"},
      {"ID": "303", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "131"},
      {"ID": "304", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "131"},
      {"ID": "305", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "131"},
      {"ID": "306", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "131"},
      {"ID": "307", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "132"},
      {"ID": "308", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "132"},
      {"ID": "309", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "132"},
      {"ID": "310", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "132"},
      {"ID": "311", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "312", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "313", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "314", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "315", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "316", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "134"},
      {"ID": "317", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "135"},
      {"ID": "318", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "136"},
      {"ID": "319", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "136"},
      {"ID": "320", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "137"},
      {"ID": "321", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "137"},
      {"ID": "322", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "138"},
      {"ID": "323", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "138"},
      {"ID": "324", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "139"},
      {"ID": "325", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "139"},
      {"ID": "326", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "140"},
      {"ID": "327", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "140"},
      {"ID": "328", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "141"},
      {"ID": "329", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "141"},
      {"ID": "330", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "142"},
      {"ID": "331", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "142"},
      {"ID": "332", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "142"},
      {"ID": "333", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "142"},
      {"ID": "334", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "143"},
      {"ID": "335", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "143"},
      {"ID": "336", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "143"},
      {"ID": "337", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "143"},
      {"ID": "338", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "144"},
      {"ID": "339", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "144"},
      {"ID": "340", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "144"},
      {"ID": "341", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "144"},
      {"ID": "342", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "145"},
      {"ID": "343", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "145"},
      {"ID": "344", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "145"},
      {"ID": "345", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "145"},
      {"ID": "346", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "146"},
      {"ID": "347", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "146"},
      {"ID": "348", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "146"},
      {"ID": "349", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "146"},
      {"ID": "350", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "147"},
      {"ID": "351", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "148"},
      {"ID": "352", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "149"},
      {"ID": "353", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "150"},
      {"ID": "354", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "151"},
      {"ID": "355", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "152"},
      {"ID": "356", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "152"},
      {"ID": "357", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "153"},
      {"ID": "358", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "153"},
      {"ID": "359", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "154"},
      {"ID": "360", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "154"},
      {"ID": "361", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "155"},
      {"ID": "362", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "155"},
      {"ID": "363", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "156"},
      {"ID": "364", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "156"},
      {"ID": "365", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "157"},
      {"ID": "366", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "157"},
      {"ID": "367", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "157"},
      {"ID": "368", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "157"},
      {"ID": "369", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "158"},
      {"ID": "370", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "158"},
      {"ID": "371", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "158"},
      {"ID": "372", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "158"},
      {"ID": "373", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "159"},
      {"ID": "374", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "159"},
      {"ID": "375", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "159"},
      {"ID": "376", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "159"},
      {"ID": "377", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "160"},
      {"ID": "378", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "160"},
      {"ID": "379", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "160"},
      {"ID": "380", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "160"},
      {"ID": "381", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "161"},
      {"ID": "382", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "161"},
      {"ID": "383", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "161"},
      {"ID": "384", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "161"},
      {"ID": "385", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "162"},
      {"ID": "386", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "163"},
      {"ID": "387", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "164"},
      {"ID": "388", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "165"},
      {"ID": "389", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "165"},
      {"ID": "390", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "166"},
      {"ID": "391", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "166"},
      {"ID": "392", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "167"},
      {"ID": "393", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "167"},
      {"ID": "394", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "168"},
      {"ID": "395", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "168"},
      {"ID": "396", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "169"},
      {"ID": "397", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "169"},
      {"ID": "398", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "170"},
      {"ID": "399", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "170"},
      {"ID": "400", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "171"},
      {"ID": "401", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "171"},
      {"ID": "402", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "171"},
      {"ID": "403", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "171"},
      {"ID": "404", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "172"},
      {"ID": "405", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "172"},
      {"ID": "406", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "172"},
      {"ID": "407", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "172"},
      {"ID": "408", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "173"},
      {"ID": "409", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "173"},
      {"ID": "410", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "173"},
      {"ID": "411", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "173"},
      {"ID": "412", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "174"},
      {"ID": "413", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "174"},
      {"ID": "414", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "174"},
      {"ID": "415", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "174"},
      {"ID": "416", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "175"},
      {"ID": "417", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "175"},
      {"ID": "418", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "175"},
      {"ID": "419", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "175"},
      {"ID": "420", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "176"},
      {"ID": "421", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "177"},
      {"ID": "422", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "178"},
      {"ID": "423", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "179"},
      {"ID": "424", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "179"},
      {"ID": "425", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "180"},
      {"ID": "426", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "180"},
      {"ID": "427", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "181"},
      {"ID": "428", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "181"},
      {"ID": "429", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "182"},
      {"ID": "430", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "182"},
      {"ID": "431", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "183"},
      {"ID": "432", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "183"},
      {"ID": "433", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "184"},
      {"ID": "434", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "184"},
      {"ID": "435", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "185"},
      {"ID": "436", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "185"},
      {"ID": "437", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "185"},
      {"ID": "438", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "185"},
      {"ID": "439", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "186"},
      {"ID": "440", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "186"},
      {"ID": "441", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "186"},
      {"ID": "442", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "186"},
      {"ID": "443", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "187"},
      {"ID": "444", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "187"},
      {"ID": "445", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "187"},
      {"ID": "446", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "187"},
      {"ID": "447", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "188"},
      {"ID": "448", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "188"},
      {"ID": "449", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "188"},
      {"ID": "450", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "188"},
      {"ID": "451", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "189"},
      {"ID": "452", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "189"},
      {"ID": "453", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "189"},
      {"ID": "454", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "189"},
      {"ID": "455", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "190"},
      {"ID": "456", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "191"},
      {"ID": "457", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "192"},
      {"ID": "458", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "193"},
      {"ID": "459", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "193"},
      {"ID": "460", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "194"},
      {"ID": "461", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "194"},
      {"ID": "462", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "195"},
      {"ID": "463", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "195"},
      {"ID": "464", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "196"},
      {"ID": "465", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "196"},
      {"ID": "466", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "197"},
      {"ID": "467", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "197"},
      {"ID": "468", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "198"},
      {"ID": "469", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "198"},
      {"ID": "540", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "199"},
      {"ID": "541", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "199"},
      {"ID": "542", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "199"},
      {"ID": "543", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "199"},
      {"ID": "544", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "200"},
      {"ID": "545", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "200"},
      {"ID": "546", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "200"},
      {"ID": "547", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "200"},
      {"ID": "548", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "201"},
      {"ID": "549", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "201"},
      {"ID": "550", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "201"},
      {"ID": "551", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "201"},
      {"ID": "552", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "202"},
      {"ID": "553", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "202"},
      {"ID": "554", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "202"},
      {"ID": "555", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "202"},
      {"ID": "556", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "203"},
      {"ID": "557", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "203"},
      {"ID": "558", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "203"},
      {"ID": "559", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "203"},
      {"ID": "560", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "204"},
      {"ID": "561", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "205"},
      {"ID": "562", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "206"},
      {"ID": "563", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "207"},
      {"ID": "564", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "207"},
      {"ID": "565", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "208"},
      {"ID": "566", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "208"},
      {"ID": "567", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "209"},
      {"ID": "568", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "209"},
      {"ID": "569", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "210"},
      {"ID": "570", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "210"},
      {"ID": "571", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "211"},
      {"ID": "572", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "211"},
      {"ID": "573", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "212"},
      {"ID": "574", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "212"},
      {"ID": "575", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "213"},
      {"ID": "576", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "213"},
      {"ID": "577", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "213"},
      {"ID": "578", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "213"},
      {"ID": "579", "OPTION": "CapsLock", "QUESTIONID": "214"},
      {"ID": "580", "OPTION": "NumLock", "QUESTIONID": "214"},
      {"ID": "581", "OPTION": "ScrolLock", "QUESTIONID": "214"},
      {"ID": "582", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "214"},
      {"ID": "583", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "215"},
      {"ID": "584", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "215"},
      {"ID": "585", "OPTION": "Charater", "QUESTIONID": "215"},
      {"ID": "586", "OPTION": "Space", "QUESTIONID": "215"},
      {"ID": "587", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "216"},
      {"ID": "588", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "216"},
      {"ID": "589", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "216"},
      {"ID": "590", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "216"},
      {"ID": "591", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "217"},
      {"ID": "592", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "217"},
      {"ID": "593", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "217"},
      {"ID": "594", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "217"},
      {"ID": "595", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "218"},
      {"ID": "596", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "219"},
      {"ID": "597", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "220"},
      {"ID": "598", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "221"},
      {"ID": "599", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "221"},
      {"ID": "600", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "222"},
      {"ID": "601", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "222"},
      {"ID": "602", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "223"},
      {"ID": "603", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "223"},
      {"ID": "604", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "224"},
      {"ID": "605", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "224"},
      {"ID": "606", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "225"},
      {"ID": "607", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "225"},
      {"ID": "608", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "226"},
      {"ID": "609", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "226"}
    ],
    "EXAM_CATEGORY_TAG_MASTER": [
      {"ID": "1", "CHAPTERID": "1", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "2", "CHAPTERID": "1", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "4", "CHAPTERID": "1", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "5"},
      {"ID": "8", "CHAPTERID": "2", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "9", "CHAPTERID": "2", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "11", "CHAPTERID": "2", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "4"},
      {"ID": "13", "CHAPTERID": "2", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "21", "CHAPTERID": "3", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "22", "CHAPTERID": "4", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "25", "CHAPTERID": "4", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "26", "CHAPTERID": "4", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "31", "CHAPTERID": "5", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "5"},
      {"ID": "36", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "37", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "38", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "4"},
      {"ID": "39", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "4"},
      {"ID": "40", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "41", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "42", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "43", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "44", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "45", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "5"},
      {"ID": "46", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "5"},
      {"ID": "47", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "48", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "49", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "50", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "51", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "52", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "5"},
      {"ID": "53", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "5"},
      {"ID": "54", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "55", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "56", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "57", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "58", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "59", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "5"},
      {"ID": "60", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "5"},
      {"ID": "61", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "62", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "63", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "64", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "65", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "66", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "67", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "68", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "69", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "70", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "75", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "76", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "77", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "78", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "79", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "80", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "81", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "82", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "83", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "84", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "85", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "86", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "87", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "88", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "89", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "90", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "91", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "3", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "92", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "6"},
      {"ID": "93", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "94", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "6"},
      {"ID": "95", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "7"},
      {"ID": "96", "CHAPTERID": "17", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "97", "CHAPTERID": "18", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "98", "CHAPTERID": "19", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "99", "CHAPTERID": "20", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "100", "CHAPTERID": "21", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "101", "CHAPTERID": "22", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "102", "CHAPTERID": "23", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "103", "CHAPTERID": "24", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "104", "CHAPTERID": "25", "CATEGORYID": "1"}
    ],
    "CHAPTER": [
      {"ID": "1", "NAME": "Parts of a Computer", "CLASSID": "1", "TID": "1"},
      {"ID": "7", "NAME": "Know Your Computer", "CLASSID": "2", "TID": "1"},
      {
        "ID": "20",
        "NAME": "Memory and Storage Devices",
        "CLASSID": "4",
        "TID": "1"
      },
      {"ID": "14", "NAME": "A Computer System", "CLASSID": "3", "TID": "1"},
      {"ID": "28", "NAME": "Types of Software", "CLASSID": "5", "TID": "1"},
      {
        "ID": "29",
        "NAME": "Advanced Features of Windows 7",
        "CLASSID": "5",
        "TID": "2"
      },
      {"ID": "15", "NAME": "Understanding Windows", "CLASSID": "3", "TID": "2"},
      {"ID": "21", "NAME": "More on Windows 7", "CLASSID": "4", "TID": "2"},
      {"ID": "8", "NAME": "Working of a Computer", "CLASSID": "2", "TID": "2"},
      {"ID": "2", "NAME": "Handling a Mouse", "CLASSID": "1", "TID": "2"},
      {"ID": "3", "NAME": "Using a Keyboard", "CLASSID": "1", "TID": "3"},
      {
        "ID": "9",
        "NAME": "Input and Output Devices",
        "CLASSID": "2",
        "TID": "3"
      },
      {
        "ID": "22",
        "NAME": "Internet of Things (IoT)",
        "CLASSID": "4",
        "TID": "3"
      },
      {"ID": "16", "NAME": "Fun with paint", "CLASSID": "3", "TID": "3"},
      {
        "ID": "30",
        "NAME": "Introduction to Artificial Intelligence",
        "CLASSID": "5",
        "TID": "3"
      },
      {"ID": "31", "NAME": "Microsoft PowerPoint", "CLASSID": "5", "TID": "4"},
      {"ID": "17", "NAME": "Word Processor", "CLASSID": "3", "TID": "4"},
      {
        "ID": "23",
        "NAME": "Formatting in Microsoft Word 2010",
        "CLASSID": "4",
        "TID": "4"
      },
      {"ID": "10", "NAME": "Storage Devices", "CLASSID": "2", "TID": "4"},
      {"ID": "4", "NAME": "Fun with Paint", "CLASSID": "1", "TID": "4"},
      {"ID": "5", "NAME": "Data and Storage", "CLASSID": "1", "TID": "5"},
      {
        "ID": "11",
        "NAME": "Drawing Shapes in Paint",
        "CLASSID": "2",
        "TID": "5"
      },
      {
        "ID": "24",
        "NAME": "Advanced Features of Microsoft Word 2010",
        "CLASSID": "4",
        "TID": "5"
      },
      {"ID": "18", "NAME": "Formatting a Document", "CLASSID": "3", "TID": "5"},
      {
        "ID": "32",
        "NAME": "Slide Organisation in PowerPoint",
        "CLASSID": "5",
        "TID": "5"
      },
      {"ID": "33", "NAME": "More About Scratch", "CLASSID": "5", "TID": "6"},
      {
        "ID": "19",
        "NAME": "Introduction to Scratch",
        "CLASSID": "3",
        "TID": "6"
      },
      {
        "ID": "25",
        "NAME": "Advanced Features of Microsoft Word 2011",
        "CLASSID": "4",
        "TID": "6"
      },
      {"ID": "12", "NAME": "More on Paint", "CLASSID": "2", "TID": "6"},
      {
        "ID": "6",
        "NAME": "Introduction to ScratchJr",
        "CLASSID": "1",
        "TID": "6"
      },
      {"ID": "13", "NAME": "Coding with ScratchJr", "CLASSID": "2", "TID": "7"},
      {"ID": "26", "NAME": "Coding in Scratch", "CLASSID": "4", "TID": "7"},
      {
        "ID": "34",
        "NAME": "Internet – Online Surfing",
        "CLASSID": "5",
        "TID": "7"
      },
      {"ID": "27", "NAME": "More on the Internet", "CLASSID": "4", "TID": "8"}
    ],
    "CATEGORY_MASTER": [ 
      {"ID": "1", "NAME": "General Round", "ACTIVE": "true"},
      {"ID": "2", "NAME": "G.K. Round", "ACTIVE": "true"},
      {"ID": "3", "NAME": "Abbreviation Round", "ACTIVE": "true"},
      {"ID": "4", "NAME": "Rapid Fire Round", "ACTIVE": "true"},
      {"ID": "5", "NAME": "Multiple Choice Round", "ACTIVE": "true"},
      {"ID": "6", "NAME": "Jumbled Words Round", "ACTIVE": "true"},
      {"ID": "7", "NAME": "Fill In The Missing Letters Round", "ACTIVE": "true"}
    ],

    "CATEGORY_TAG_MASTER": [
      {"ID": "1", "CHAPTERID": "1", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "2", "CHAPTERID": "1", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "3", "CHAPTERID": "2", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "4", "CHAPTERID": "2", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "5", "CHAPTERID": "2", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "6", "CHAPTERID": "2", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "7", "CHAPTERID": "3", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "8", "CHAPTERID": "3", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "9", "CHAPTERID": "4", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "10", "CHAPTERID": "4", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "11", "CHAPTERID": "5", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "12", "CHAPTERID": "5", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "13", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "14", "CHAPTERID": "6", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "15", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "16", "CHAPTERID": "7", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "17", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "18", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "19", "CHAPTERID": "8", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "20", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "21", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "22", "CHAPTERID": "9", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "23", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "24", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "25", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "26", "CHAPTERID": "10", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "27", "CHAPTERID": "11", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "28", "CHAPTERID": "11", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "29", "CHAPTERID": "11", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "30", "CHAPTERID": "12", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "31", "CHAPTERID": "12", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "32", "CHAPTERID": "12", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "33", "CHAPTERID": "13", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "34", "CHAPTERID": "13", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "35", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "36", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "37", "CHAPTERID": "14", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "38", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "39", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "40", "CHAPTERID": "15", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "41", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "42", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "43", "CHAPTERID": "16", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "44", "CHAPTERID": "17", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "45", "CHAPTERID": "17", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "46", "CHAPTERID": "17", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "47", "CHAPTERID": "18", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "48", "CHAPTERID": "18", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "49", "CHAPTERID": "18", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "50", "CHAPTERID": "19", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "51", "CHAPTERID": "19", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "52", "CHAPTERID": "19", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "53", "CHAPTERID": "20", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "54", "CHAPTERID": "20", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "55", "CHAPTERID": "20", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "56", "CHAPTERID": "21", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "57", "CHAPTERID": "21", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "58", "CHAPTERID": "21", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "59", "CHAPTERID": "22", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "60", "CHAPTERID": "22", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "61", "CHAPTERID": "22", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "62", "CHAPTERID": "23", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "63", "CHAPTERID": "23", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "64", "CHAPTERID": "23", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "65", "CHAPTERID": "24", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "66", "CHAPTERID": "25", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "67", "CHAPTERID": "24", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "68", "CHAPTERID": "24", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "69", "CHAPTERID": "26", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "70", "CHAPTERID": "26", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "71", "CHAPTERID": "26", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "72", "CHAPTERID": "26", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "73", "CHAPTERID": "27", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "74", "CHAPTERID": "27", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "75", "CHAPTERID": "27", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "76", "CHAPTERID": "28", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "77", "CHAPTERID": "28", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "78", "CHAPTERID": "28", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "79", "CHAPTERID": "29", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "80", "CHAPTERID": "29", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "81", "CHAPTERID": "29", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "82", "CHAPTERID": "30", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "83", "CHAPTERID": "30", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "84", "CHAPTERID": "31", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "85", "CHAPTERID": "31", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "86", "CHAPTERID": "31", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "87", "CHAPTERID": "32", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "88", "CHAPTERID": "32", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "89", "CHAPTERID": "32", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "90", "CHAPTERID": "32", "CATEGORYID": "2"},
      {"ID": "91", "CHAPTERID": "33", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "92", "CHAPTERID": "33", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "93", "CHAPTERID": "33", "CATEGORYID": "5"},
      {"ID": "94", "CHAPTERID": "34", "CATEGORYID": "1"},
      {"ID": "95", "CHAPTERID": "34", "CATEGORYID": "4", "TIME": "1"},
      {"ID": "96", "CHAPTERID": "34", "CATEGORYID": "5"}
    ],
    "OPTION_MASTER": [
      {"ID": "1", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "1"},
      {"ID": "2", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "1"},
      {"ID": "3", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "1"},
      {"ID": "4", "OPTION": "CPU", "QUESTIONID": "2"},
      {"ID": "5", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "2"},
      {"ID": "6", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "2"},
      {"ID": "7", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "3"},
      {"ID": "8", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "3"},
      {"ID": "9", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "3"},
      {"ID": "10", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "4"},
      {"ID": "11", "OPTION": "CPU", "QUESTIONID": "4"},
      {"ID": "12", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "4"},
      {"ID": "13", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "5"},
      {"ID": "14", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "5"},
      {"ID": "15", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "5"},
      {"ID": "16", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "5"},
      {"ID": "17", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "6"},
      {"ID": "18", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "6"},
      {"ID": "19", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "6"},
      {"ID": "20", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "6"},
      {"ID": "21", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "7"},
      {"ID": "22", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "7"},
      {"ID": "23", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "7"},
      {"ID": "24", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "7"},
      {"ID": "25", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "8"},
      {"ID": "26", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "8"},
      {"ID": "27", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "8"},
      {"ID": "28", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "8"},
      {"ID": "29", "OPTION": "One", "QUESTIONID": "9"},
      {"ID": "30", "OPTION": "Two", "QUESTIONID": "9"},
      {"ID": "31", "OPTION": "Three", "QUESTIONID": "9"},
      {"ID": "32", "OPTION": "Right-click", "QUESTIONID": "10"},
      {"ID": "33", "OPTION": "Double-click", "QUESTIONID": "10"},
      {"ID": "34", "OPTION": "Left-click", "QUESTIONID": "10"},
      {"ID": "35", "OPTION": "Mouse Pad", "QUESTIONID": "11"},
      {"ID": "36", "OPTION": "Touchpad", "QUESTIONID": "11"},
      {"ID": "37", "OPTION": "Keypad", "QUESTIONID": "11"},
      {"ID": "38", "OPTION": "Double-clicking", "QUESTIONID": "12"},
      {"ID": "39", "OPTION": "Mouse Pointer", "QUESTIONID": "12"},
      {"ID": "40", "OPTION": "Mouse Pad", "QUESTIONID": "12"},
      {"ID": "41", "OPTION": "Mouse Pad", "QUESTIONID": "13"},
      {"ID": "42", "OPTION": "Double-clicking", "QUESTIONID": "13"},
      {"ID": "43", "OPTION": "Mouse Pointer", "QUESTIONID": "13"},
      {"ID": "44", "OPTION": "Mouse Pointer", "QUESTIONID": "14"},
      {"ID": "45", "OPTION": "Mouse Pad", "QUESTIONID": "14"},
      {"ID": "46", "OPTION": "Double-clicking", "QUESTIONID": "14"},
      {"ID": "47", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "15"},
      {"ID": "48", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "15"},
      {"ID": "49", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "16"},
      {"ID": "50", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "16"},
      {"ID": "51", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "17"},
      {"ID": "52", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "17"},
      {"ID": "53", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "18"},
      {"ID": "54", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "18"},
      {"ID": "55", "OPTION": "Drag and Drop", "QUESTIONID": "19"},
      {"ID": "56", "OPTION": "Left", "QUESTIONID": "20"},
      {"ID": "57", "OPTION": "9", "QUESTIONID": "21"},
      {"ID": "58", "OPTION": "10", "QUESTIONID": "21"},
      {"ID": "59", "OPTION": "26", "QUESTIONID": "21"},
      {"ID": "60", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "22"},
      {"ID": "61", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "22"},
      {"ID": "62", "OPTION": "Backspace", "QUESTIONID": "22"},
      {"ID": "63", "OPTION": "Number", "QUESTIONID": "23"},
      {"ID": "64", "OPTION": "Special", "QUESTIONID": "23"},
      {"ID": "65", "OPTION": "Alphabet", "QUESTIONID": "23"},
      {"ID": "66", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "24"},
      {"ID": "67", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "24"},
      {"ID": "68", "OPTION": "Alphabet", "QUESTIONID": "24"},
      {"ID": "69", "OPTION": "Alphabet", "QUESTIONID": "25"},
      {"ID": "70", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "25"},
      {"ID": "71", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "25"},
      {"ID": "72", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "26"},
      {"ID": "73", "OPTION": "Alphabet", "QUESTIONID": "26"},
      {"ID": "74", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "26"},
      {"ID": "75", "OPTION": "Shapes", "QUESTIONID": "27"},
      {"ID": "76", "OPTION": "Close", "QUESTIONID": "27"},
      {"ID": "77", "OPTION": "Fill with color", "QUESTIONID": "27"},
      {"ID": "78", "OPTION": "Fill with color", "QUESTIONID": "28"},
      {"ID": "79", "OPTION": "Shapes", "QUESTIONID": "28"},
      {"ID": "80", "OPTION": "Close", "QUESTIONID": "28"},
      {"ID": "81", "OPTION": "Close", "QUESTIONID": "29"},
      {"ID": "82", "OPTION": "Fill with color", "QUESTIONID": "29"},
      {"ID": "83", "OPTION": "Shapes", "QUESTIONID": "29"},
      {"ID": "84", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "30"},
      {"ID": "85", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "30"},
      {"ID": "86", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "31"},
      {"ID": "87", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "31"},
      {"ID": "88", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "32"},
      {"ID": "89", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "32"},
      {"ID": "90", "OPTION": "Books", "QUESTIONID": "33"},
      {"ID": "91", "OPTION": "Pictures", "QUESTIONID": "33"},
      {"ID": "92", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "33"},
      {"ID": "93", "OPTION": "Water", "QUESTIONID": "34"},
      {"ID": "94", "OPTION": "Clothes", "QUESTIONID": "34"},
      {"ID": "95", "OPTION": "Pen", "QUESTIONID": "34"},
      {"ID": "96", "OPTION": "Storage Places", "QUESTIONID": "35"},
      {"ID": "97", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "35"},
      {"ID": "98", "OPTION": "Hard Disk", "QUESTIONID": "35"},
      {"ID": "99", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "36"},
      {"ID": "100", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "36"},
      {"ID": "101", "OPTION": "CD", "QUESTIONID": "36"},
      {"ID": "102", "OPTION": "CD", "QUESTIONID": "37"},
      {"ID": "103", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "37"},
      {"ID": "104", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "37"},
      {"ID": "105", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "38"},
      {"ID": "106", "OPTION": "CD", "QUESTIONID": "38"},
      {"ID": "107", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "38"},
      {"ID": "108", "OPTION": "Blocks Palette", "QUESTIONID": "39"},
      {"ID": "109", "OPTION": "Coding Area", "QUESTIONID": "39"},
      {"ID": "110", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "39"},
      {"ID": "111", "OPTION": "Green Flag", "QUESTIONID": "40"},
      {"ID": "112", "OPTION": "Block Categories", "QUESTIONID": "40"},
      {"ID": "113", "OPTION": "Blocks Palette", "QUESTIONID": "40"},
      {"ID": "114", "OPTION": "Hop", "QUESTIONID": "41"},
      {"ID": "115", "OPTION": "Go Home", "QUESTIONID": "41"},
      {"ID": "116", "OPTION": "Reset", "QUESTIONID": "41"},
      {"ID": "117", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "42"},
      {"ID": "118", "OPTION": "Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "43"},
      {"ID": "119", "OPTION": "Plus", "QUESTIONID": "44"},
      {"ID": "120", "OPTION": "Schools", "QUESTIONID": "45"},
      {"ID": "121", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "45"},
      {"ID": "122", "OPTION": "Tasks", "QUESTIONID": "45"},
      {"ID": "123", "OPTION": "Humans", "QUESTIONID": "45"},
      {"ID": "124", "OPTION": "Humans", "QUESTIONID": "46"},
      {"ID": "125", "OPTION": "Schools", "QUESTIONID": "46"},
      {"ID": "126", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "46"},
      {"ID": "127", "OPTION": "Tasks", "QUESTIONID": "46"},
      {"ID": "128", "OPTION": "Tasks", "QUESTIONID": "47"},
      {"ID": "129", "OPTION": "Humans", "QUESTIONID": "47"},
      {"ID": "130", "OPTION": "Schools", "QUESTIONID": "47"},
      {"ID": "131", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "47"},
      {"ID": "132", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "48"},
      {"ID": "133", "OPTION": "Tasks", "QUESTIONID": "48"},
      {"ID": "134", "OPTION": "Humans", "QUESTIONID": "48"},
      {"ID": "135", "OPTION": "Schools", "QUESTIONID": "48"},
      {"ID": "136", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "49"},
      {"ID": "137", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "49"},
      {"ID": "138", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "50"},
      {"ID": "139", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "50"},
      {"ID": "140", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "51"},
      {"ID": "141", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "51"},
      {"ID": "142", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "52"},
      {"ID": "143", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "52"},
      {"ID": "144", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "53"},
      {"ID": "145", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "53"},
      {"ID": "146", "OPTION": "CPU", "QUESTIONID": "53"},
      {"ID": "147", "OPTION": "IPO", "QUESTIONID": "54"},
      {"ID": "148", "OPTION": "POI", "QUESTIONID": "54"},
      {"ID": "149", "OPTION": "IOP", "QUESTIONID": "54"},
      {"ID": "150", "OPTION": "Input", "QUESTIONID": "55"},
      {"ID": "151", "OPTION": "Output", "QUESTIONID": "55"},
      {"ID": "152", "OPTION": "Processing", "QUESTIONID": "55"},
      {"ID": "153", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "56"},
      {"ID": "154", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "56"},
      {"ID": "155", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "57"},
      {"ID": "156", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "57"},
      {"ID": "157", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "58"},
      {"ID": "158", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "58"},
      {"ID": "159", "OPTION": "Central Processing Unit", "QUESTIONID": "59"},
      {"ID": "160", "OPTION": "Input-Process-Output", "QUESTIONID": "60"},
      {"ID": "161", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "61"},
      {"ID": "162", "OPTION": "Joystick", "QUESTIONID": "62"},
      {"ID": "163", "OPTION": "Web Camera", "QUESTIONID": "62"},
      {"ID": "164", "OPTION": "Barcode Reader", "QUESTIONID": "62"},
      {"ID": "165", "OPTION": "Web Camera", "QUESTIONID": "63"},
      {"ID": "166", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "63"},
      {"ID": "167", "OPTION": "Light Pen", "QUESTIONID": "63"},
      {"ID": "168", "OPTION": "Barcode Reader", "QUESTIONID": "64"},
      {"ID": "169", "OPTION": "Scanner", "QUESTIONID": "64"},
      {"ID": "170", "OPTION": "Web Camera", "QUESTIONID": "64"},
      {"ID": "171", "OPTION": "CRT", "QUESTIONID": "65"},
      {"ID": "172", "OPTION": "VDU", "QUESTIONID": "65"},
      {"ID": "173", "OPTION": "LED", "QUESTIONID": "65"},
      {"ID": "174", "OPTION": "Headphones", "QUESTIONID": "66"},
      {"ID": "175", "OPTION": "Speaker", "QUESTIONID": "66"},
      {"ID": "176", "OPTION": "Printer", "QUESTIONID": "66"},
      {"ID": "177", "OPTION": "Enter", "QUESTIONID": "67"},
      {"ID": "178", "OPTION": "Spacebar", "QUESTIONID": "67"},
      {"ID": "179", "OPTION": "Arrow", "QUESTIONID": "67"},
      {"ID": "180", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "68"},
      {"ID": "181", "OPTION": "Microphone", "QUESTIONID": "68"},
      {"ID": "182", "OPTION": "Arrow", "QUESTIONID": "68"},
      {"ID": "183", "OPTION": "Speaker", "QUESTIONID": "68"},
      {"ID": "184", "OPTION": "Output", "QUESTIONID": "69"},
      {"ID": "185", "OPTION": "Hard Copy", "QUESTIONID": "69"},
      {"ID": "186", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "69"},
      {"ID": "187", "OPTION": "Microphone", "QUESTIONID": "69"},
      {"ID": "188", "OPTION": "Arrow", "QUESTIONID": "70"},
      {"ID": "189", "OPTION": "Speaker", "QUESTIONID": "70"},
      {"ID": "190", "OPTION": "Output", "QUESTIONID": "70"},
      {"ID": "191", "OPTION": "Hard Copy", "QUESTIONID": "70"},
      {"ID": "192", "OPTION": "Hard Copy", "QUESTIONID": "71"},
      {"ID": "193", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "71"},
      {"ID": "194", "OPTION": "Microphone", "QUESTIONID": "71"},
      {"ID": "195", "OPTION": "Arrow", "QUESTIONID": "71"},
      {"ID": "196", "OPTION": "Speaker", "QUESTIONID": "72"},
      {"ID": "197", "OPTION": "Output", "QUESTIONID": "72"},
      {"ID": "198", "OPTION": "Hard Copy", "QUESTIONID": "72"},
      {"ID": "199", "OPTION": "Mouse", "QUESTIONID": "72"},
      {"ID": "200", "OPTION": "Microphone", "QUESTIONID": "73"},
      {"ID": "201", "OPTION": "Arrow", "QUESTIONID": "73"},
      {"ID": "202", "OPTION": "Speaker", "QUESTIONID": "73"},
      {"ID": "203", "OPTION": "Output", "QUESTIONID": "73"},
      {"ID": "204", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "74"},
      {"ID": "205", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "74"},
      {"ID": "206", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "75"},
      {"ID": "207", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "75"},
      {"ID": "208", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "76"},
      {"ID": "209", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "76"},
      {"ID": "210", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "77"},
      {"ID": "211", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "77"},
      {"ID": "212", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "78"},
      {"ID": "213", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "78"},
      {"ID": "214", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "79"},
      {"ID": "215", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "79"},
      {"ID": "216", "OPTION": "CD", "QUESTIONID": "80"},
      {"ID": "217", "OPTION": "Hard Disk", "QUESTIONID": "80"},
      {"ID": "218", "OPTION": "Memory Card", "QUESTIONID": "80"},
      {"ID": "219", "OPTION": "Compact Disc", "QUESTIONID": "81"},
      {"ID": "220", "OPTION": "Common Disc", "QUESTIONID": "81"},
      {"ID": "221", "OPTION": "Computer Disc", "QUESTIONID": "81"},
      {"ID": "222", "OPTION": "Hard Drive", "QUESTIONID": "82"},
      {"ID": "223", "OPTION": "Flash Drive", "QUESTIONID": "82"},
      {"ID": "224", "OPTION": "CD Drive", "QUESTIONID": "82"},
      {"ID": "225", "OPTION": "CD", "QUESTIONID": "83"},
      {"ID": "226", "OPTION": "DVD", "QUESTIONID": "83"},
      {"ID": "227", "OPTION": "Memory Card", "QUESTIONID": "83"},
      {"ID": "228", "OPTION": "Digital Versatile Disc", "QUESTIONID": "84"},
      {"ID": "229", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "84"},
      {"ID": "230", "OPTION": "Hard Disk", "QUESTIONID": "84"},
      {"ID": "231", "OPTION": "Blu-ray Disc", "QUESTIONID": "84"},
      {"ID": "232", "OPTION": "Blu-ray Disc", "QUESTIONID": "85"},
      {"ID": "233", "OPTION": "Digital Versatile Disc", "QUESTIONID": "85"},
      {"ID": "234", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "85"},
      {"ID": "235", "OPTION": "Hard Disk", "QUESTIONID": "85"},
      {"ID": "236", "OPTION": "Hard Disk", "QUESTIONID": "86"},
      {"ID": "237", "OPTION": "Blu-ray Disc", "QUESTIONID": "86"},
      {"ID": "238", "OPTION": "Digital Versatile Disc", "QUESTIONID": "86"},
      {"ID": "239", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "86"},
      {"ID": "240", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "87"},
      {"ID": "241", "OPTION": "Hard Disk", "QUESTIONID": "87"},
      {"ID": "242", "OPTION": "Blu-ray Disc", "QUESTIONID": "87"},
      {"ID": "243", "OPTION": "Digital Versatile Disc", "QUESTIONID": "87"},
      {"ID": "244", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "88"},
      {"ID": "245", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "88"},
      {"ID": "246", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "89"},
      {"ID": "247", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "89"},
      {"ID": "248", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "90"},
      {"ID": "249", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "90"},
      {"ID": "250", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "91"},
      {"ID": "251", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "91"},
      {"ID": "252", "OPTION": "USB", "QUESTIONID": "92"},
      {"ID": "253", "OPTION": "Memory Card", "QUESTIONID": "93"},
      {"ID": "254", "OPTION": "Drawing Area", "QUESTIONID": "94"},
      {"ID": "255", "OPTION": "Shapes Group", "QUESTIONID": "94"},
      {"ID": "256", "OPTION": "Tools Group", "QUESTIONID": "94"},
      {"ID": "257", "OPTION": "Circle", "QUESTIONID": "95"},
      {"ID": "258", "OPTION": "Line", "QUESTIONID": "95"},
      {"ID": "259", "OPTION": "Curve", "QUESTIONID": "95"},
      {"ID": "260", "OPTION": "Line", "QUESTIONID": "96"},
      {"ID": "261", "OPTION": "Shape", "QUESTIONID": "96"},
      {"ID": "262", "OPTION": "Filled", "QUESTIONID": "96"},
      {"ID": "263", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "97"},
      {"ID": "264", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "97"},
      {"ID": "265", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "98"},
      {"ID": "266", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "98"},
      {"ID": "267", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "99"},
      {"ID": "268", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "99"},
      {"ID": "269", "OPTION": "Six", "QUESTIONID": "100"},
      {"ID": "270", "OPTION": "Two", "QUESTIONID": "101"},
      {"ID": "271", "OPTION": "Eraser", "QUESTIONID": "102"},
      {"ID": "272", "OPTION": "Pencil", "QUESTIONID": "102"},
      {"ID": "273", "OPTION": "Fill with Color", "QUESTIONID": "102"},
      {"ID": "274", "OPTION": "Select", "QUESTIONID": "103"},
      {"ID": "275", "OPTION": "Fill with color", "QUESTIONID": "103"},
      {"ID": "276", "OPTION": "Pencil", "QUESTIONID": "103"},
      {"ID": "277", "OPTION": "Open", "QUESTIONID": "104"},
      {"ID": "278", "OPTION": "Curve", "QUESTIONID": "104"},
      {"ID": "279", "OPTION": "Closed", "QUESTIONID": "104"},
      {"ID": "280", "OPTION": "Eraser", "QUESTIONID": "105"},
      {"ID": "281", "OPTION": "Paint", "QUESTIONID": "105"},
      {"ID": "282", "OPTION": "Text", "QUESTIONID": "105"},
      {"ID": "283", "OPTION": "Text", "QUESTIONID": "106"},
      {"ID": "284", "OPTION": "Eraser", "QUESTIONID": "106"},
      {"ID": "285", "OPTION": "Paint", "QUESTIONID": "106"},
      {"ID": "286", "OPTION": "Paint", "QUESTIONID": "107"},
      {"ID": "287", "OPTION": "Text", "QUESTIONID": "107"},
      {"ID": "288", "OPTION": "Eraser", "QUESTIONID": "107"},
      {"ID": "289", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "108"},
      {"ID": "290", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "108"},
      {"ID": "291", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "109"},
      {"ID": "292", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "109"},
      {"ID": "293", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "110"},
      {"ID": "294", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "110"},
      {"ID": "295", "OPTION": "Motion", "QUESTIONID": "111"},
      {"ID": "296", "OPTION": "Looks", "QUESTIONID": "111"},
      {"ID": "297", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "111"},
      {"ID": "298", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "112"},
      {"ID": "299", "OPTION": "Motion", "QUESTIONID": "112"},
      {"ID": "300", "OPTION": "Looks", "QUESTIONID": "112"},
      {"ID": "301", "OPTION": "Looks", "QUESTIONID": "113"},
      {"ID": "302", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "113"},
      {"ID": "303", "OPTION": "Motion", "QUESTIONID": "113"},
      {"ID": "304", "OPTION": "Six", "QUESTIONID": "114"},
      {"ID": "305", "OPTION": "Green colour", "QUESTIONID": "115"},
      {"ID": "306", "OPTION": "Triggering Blocks", "QUESTIONID": "116"},
      {"ID": "307", "OPTION": "Data, Instructions", "QUESTIONID": "117"},
      {"ID": "308", "OPTION": "Hardware, Navigation", "QUESTIONID": "117"},
      {"ID": "309", "OPTION": "Instructions, Data", "QUESTIONID": "117"},
      {"ID": "310", "OPTION": "Navigation, Hardware", "QUESTIONID": "117"},
      {"ID": "311", "OPTION": "Hardware", "QUESTIONID": "118"},
      {"ID": "312", "OPTION": "Navigation", "QUESTIONID": "118"},
      {"ID": "313", "OPTION": "Numeric keypad", "QUESTIONID": "118"},
      {"ID": "314", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "118"},
      {"ID": "315", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "119"},
      {"ID": "316", "OPTION": "Instructions", "QUESTIONID": "119"},
      {"ID": "317", "OPTION": "Navigation", "QUESTIONID": "119"},
      {"ID": "318", "OPTION": "Numeric keypad", "QUESTIONID": "119"},
      {"ID": "319", "OPTION": "Numeric keypad", "QUESTIONID": "120"},
      {"ID": "320", "OPTION": "Hardware", "QUESTIONID": "120"},
      {"ID": "321", "OPTION": "Data", "QUESTIONID": "120"},
      {"ID": "322", "OPTION": "Instructions", "QUESTIONID": "120"},
      {"ID": "323", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "121"},
      {"ID": "324", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "121"},
      {"ID": "325", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "122"},
      {"ID": "326", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "122"},
      {"ID": "327", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "123"},
      {"ID": "328", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "123"},
      {"ID": "329", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "124"},
      {"ID": "330", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "124"},
      {"ID": "331", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "125"},
      {"ID": "332", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "125"},
      {"ID": "333", "OPTION": "Input", "QUESTIONID": "126"},
      {"ID": "334", "OPTION": "Process", "QUESTIONID": "126"},
      {"ID": "335", "OPTION": "Output", "QUESTIONID": "126"},
      {"ID": "336", "OPTION": "LCD", "QUESTIONID": "127"},
      {"ID": "337", "OPTION": "CRT", "QUESTIONID": "127"},
      {"ID": "338", "OPTION": "LED", "QUESTIONID": "127"},
      {"ID": "339", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "128"},
      {"ID": "340", "OPTION": "Typing", "QUESTIONID": "128"},
      {"ID": "341", "OPTION": "Navigation", "QUESTIONID": "128"},
      {"ID": "342", "OPTION": "Monitor", "QUESTIONID": "129"},
      {"ID": "343", "OPTION": "CPU", "QUESTIONID": "129"},
      {"ID": "344", "OPTION": "Keyboard", "QUESTIONID": "129"},
      {"ID": "345", "OPTION": "Notification Area", "QUESTIONID": "130"},
      {"ID": "346", "OPTION": "Desktop", "QUESTIONID": "130"},
      {"ID": "347", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "130"},
      {"ID": "348", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "130"},
      {"ID": "349", "OPTION": "Operating system", "QUESTIONID": "131"},
      {"ID": "350", "OPTION": "Sorting", "QUESTIONID": "131"},
      {"ID": "351", "OPTION": "Notification Area", "QUESTIONID": "131"},
      {"ID": "352", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "131"},
      {"ID": "353", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "132"},
      {"ID": "354", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "132"},
      {"ID": "355", "OPTION": "Operating system", "QUESTIONID": "132"},
      {"ID": "356", "OPTION": "Notification Area", "QUESTIONID": "132"},
      {"ID": "357", "OPTION": "Sorting", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "358", "OPTION": "Notification Area", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "359", "OPTION": "Desktop", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "360", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "133"},
      {"ID": "361", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "134"},
      {"ID": "362", "OPTION": "Operating system", "QUESTIONID": "134"},
      {"ID": "363", "OPTION": "Sorting", "QUESTIONID": "134"},
      {"ID": "364", "OPTION": "Notification Area", "QUESTIONID": "134"},
      {"ID": "365", "OPTION": "Desktop", "QUESTIONID": "135"},
      {"ID": "366", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "135"},
      {"ID": "367", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "135"},
      {"ID": "368", "OPTION": "Operating system", "QUESTIONID": "135"},
      {"ID": "369", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "136"},
      {"ID": "370", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "136"},
      {"ID": "371", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "137"},
      {"ID": "372", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "137"},
      {"ID": "373", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "138"},
      {"ID": "374", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "138"},
      {"ID": "375", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "139"},
      {"ID": "376", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "139"},
      {"ID": "377", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "140"},
      {"ID": "378", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "140"},
      {"ID": "379", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "141"},
      {"ID": "380", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "141"},
      {"ID": "381", "OPTION": "Screen Saver", "QUESTIONID": "142"},
      {"ID": "382", "OPTION": "Desktop", "QUESTIONID": "142"},
      {"ID": "383", "OPTION": "Operating System", "QUESTIONID": "142"},
      {"ID": "384", "OPTION": "Left", "QUESTIONID": "143"},
      {"ID": "385", "OPTION": "Right", "QUESTIONID": "143"},
      {"ID": "386", "OPTION": "Double", "QUESTIONID": "143"},
      {"ID": "387", "OPTION": "Start Button", "QUESTIONID": "144"},
      {"ID": "388", "OPTION": "File Menu", "QUESTIONID": "144"},
      {"ID": "389", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "144"},
      {"ID": "390", "OPTION": "Apple", "QUESTIONID": "145"},
      {"ID": "391", "OPTION": "Microsoft", "QUESTIONID": "145"},
      {"ID": "392", "OPTION": "Linux", "QUESTIONID": "145"},
      {"ID": "393", "OPTION": "Screen Saver", "QUESTIONID": "146"},
      {"ID": "394", "OPTION": "Gadgets", "QUESTIONID": "146"},
      {"ID": "395", "OPTION": "Start Menu", "QUESTIONID": "146"},
      {"ID": "396", "OPTION": "Curves", "QUESTIONID": "147"},
      {"ID": "397", "OPTION": "Three", "QUESTIONID": "147"},
      {"ID": "398", "OPTION": "Rectangle", "QUESTIONID": "147"},
      {"ID": "399", "OPTION": "Select", "QUESTIONID": "147"},
      {"ID": "400", "OPTION": "Select", "QUESTIONID": "148"},
      {"ID": "401", "OPTION": "Curves", "QUESTIONID": "148"},
      {"ID": "402", "OPTION": "Three", "QUESTIONID": "148"},
      {"ID": "403", "OPTION": "Color Picker", "QUESTIONID": "148"},
      {"ID": "404", "OPTION": "Color Picker", "QUESTIONID": "149"},
      {"ID": "405", "OPTION": "Rectangle", "QUESTIONID": "149"},
      {"ID": "406", "OPTION": "Select", "QUESTIONID": "149"},
      {"ID": "407", "OPTION": "Curves", "QUESTIONID": "149"},
      {"ID": "408", "OPTION": "Three", "QUESTIONID": "150"},
      {"ID": "409", "OPTION": "Color Picker", "QUESTIONID": "150"},
      {"ID": "410", "OPTION": "Rectangle", "QUESTIONID": "150"},
      {"ID": "411", "OPTION": "Select", "QUESTIONID": "150"},
      {"ID": "412", "OPTION": "Rectangle", "QUESTIONID": "151"},
      {"ID": "413", "OPTION": "Select", "QUESTIONID": "151"},
      {"ID": "414", "OPTION": "Curves", "QUESTIONID": "151"},
      {"ID": "415", "OPTION": "Three", "QUESTIONID": "151"},
      {"ID": "416", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "152"},
      {"ID": "417", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "152"},
      {"ID": "418", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "153"},
      {"ID": "419", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "153"},
      {"ID": "420", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "154"},
      {"ID": "421", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "154"},
      {"ID": "422", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "155"},
      {"ID": "423", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "155"},
      {"ID": "424", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "156"},
      {"ID": "425", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "156"},
      {"ID": "426", "OPTION": "Select", "QUESTIONID": "157"},
      {"ID": "427", "OPTION": "Zoom", "QUESTIONID": "157"},
      {"ID": "428", "OPTION": "Rotate", "QUESTIONID": "157"},
      {"ID": "429", "OPTION": "Copy", "QUESTIONID": "158"},
      {"ID": "430", "OPTION": "Crop", "QUESTIONID": "158"},
      {"ID": "431", "OPTION": "Move", "QUESTIONID": "158"},
      {"ID": "432", "OPTION": "Rectangular Selection", "QUESTIONID": "159"},
      {"ID": "433", "OPTION": "Free-form Selection", "QUESTIONID": "159"},
      {"ID": "434", "OPTION": "Select", "QUESTIONID": "159"},
      {"ID": "435", "OPTION": "Ctrl + Z", "QUESTIONID": "160"},
      {"ID": "436", "OPTION": "Ctrl + N", "QUESTIONID": "160"},
      {"ID": "437", "OPTION": "Ctrl + S", "QUESTIONID": "160"},
      {"ID": "438", "OPTION": "Rotate", "QUESTIONID": "161"},
      {"ID": "439", "OPTION": "Resize", "QUESTIONID": "161"},
      {"ID": "440", "OPTION": "Move", "QUESTIONID": "161"},
      {"ID": "441", "OPTION": "Blank", "QUESTIONID": "162"},
      {"ID": "442", "OPTION": "Selection Area", "QUESTIONID": "162"},
      {"ID": "443", "OPTION": "Undo", "QUESTIONID": "162"},
      {"ID": "444", "OPTION": "Thesaurus", "QUESTIONID": "162"},
      {"ID": "445", "OPTION": "Red", "QUESTIONID": "163"},
      {"ID": "446", "OPTION": "Blank", "QUESTIONID": "163"},
      {"ID": "447", "OPTION": "Selection Area", "QUESTIONID": "163"},
      {"ID": "448", "OPTION": "Undo", "QUESTIONID": "163"},
      {"ID": "449", "OPTION": "Undo", "QUESTIONID": "164"},
      {"ID": "450", "OPTION": "Thesaurus", "QUESTIONID": "164"},
      {"ID": "451", "OPTION": "Red", "QUESTIONID": "164"},
      {"ID": "452", "OPTION": "Blank", "QUESTIONID": "164"},
      {"ID": "453", "OPTION": "Selection Area", "QUESTIONID": "165"},
      {"ID": "454", "OPTION": "Undo", "QUESTIONID": "165"},
      {"ID": "455", "OPTION": "Thesaurus", "QUESTIONID": "165"},
      {"ID": "456", "OPTION": "Red", "QUESTIONID": "165"},
      {"ID": "457", "OPTION": "Thesaurus", "QUESTIONID": "166"},
      {"ID": "458", "OPTION": "Red", "QUESTIONID": "166"},
      {"ID": "459", "OPTION": "Blank", "QUESTIONID": "166"},
      {"ID": "460", "OPTION": "Selection Area", "QUESTIONID": "166"},
      {"ID": "461", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "167"},
      {"ID": "462", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "167"},
      {"ID": "463", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "168"},
      {"ID": "464", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "168"},
      {"ID": "465", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "169"},
      {"ID": "466", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "169"},
      {"ID": "467", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "170"},
      {"ID": "468", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "170"},
      {"ID": "469", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "171"},
      {"ID": "470", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "171"},
      {"ID": "471", "OPTION": "Doc1", "QUESTIONID": "172"},
      {"ID": "472", "OPTION": "Document1", "QUESTIONID": "172"},
      {"ID": "473", "OPTION": "1 Document", "QUESTIONID": "172"},
      {"ID": "474", "OPTION": "Red wavy line", "QUESTIONID": "173"},
      {"ID": "475", "OPTION": "Green wavy line", "QUESTIONID": "173"},
      {"ID": "476", "OPTION": "Blue wavy line", "QUESTIONID": "173"},
      {"ID": "477", "OPTION": "Cursor", "QUESTIONID": "174"},
      {"ID": "478", "OPTION": "Arrow", "QUESTIONID": "174"},
      {"ID": "479", "OPTION": "Mouse pointer", "QUESTIONID": "174"},
      {"ID": "480", "OPTION": "Wrapping", "QUESTIONID": "175"},
      {"ID": "481", "OPTION": "Editing", "QUESTIONID": "175"},
      {"ID": "482", "OPTION": "Formatting", "QUESTIONID": "175"},
      {"ID": "483", "OPTION": "Sentence", "QUESTIONID": "176"},
      {"ID": "484", "OPTION": "Left", "QUESTIONID": "176"},
      {"ID": "485", "OPTION": "Italic", "QUESTIONID": "176"},
      {"ID": "486", "OPTION": "Bullet", "QUESTIONID": "176"},
      {"ID": "487", "OPTION": "Line Spacing", "QUESTIONID": "177"},
      {"ID": "488", "OPTION": "Sentence", "QUESTIONID": "177"},
      {"ID": "489", "OPTION": "Left", "QUESTIONID": "177"},
      {"ID": "490", "OPTION": "Italic", "QUESTIONID": "177"},
      {"ID": "491", "OPTION": "Bullet", "QUESTIONID": "178"},
      {"ID": "492", "OPTION": "Line Spacing", "QUESTIONID": "178"},
      {"ID": "493", "OPTION": "Sentence", "QUESTIONID": "178"},
      {"ID": "494", "OPTION": "Left", "QUESTIONID": "178"},
      {"ID": "495", "OPTION": "Italic", "QUESTIONID": "179"},
      {"ID": "496", "OPTION": "Bullet", "QUESTIONID": "179"},
      {"ID": "497", "OPTION": "Line Spacing", "QUESTIONID": "179"},
      {"ID": "498", "OPTION": "Sentence", "QUESTIONID": "179"},
      {"ID": "499", "OPTION": "Left", "QUESTIONID": "180"},
      {"ID": "500", "OPTION": "Italic", "QUESTIONID": "180"},
      {"ID": "501", "OPTION": "Bullet", "QUESTIONID": "180"},
      {"ID": "502", "OPTION": "Line Spacing", "QUESTIONID": "180"},
      {"ID": "503", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "181"},
      {"ID": "504", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "181"},
      {"ID": "505", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "182"},
      {"ID": "506", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "182"},
      {"ID": "507", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "183"},
      {"ID": "508", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "183"},
      {"ID": "509", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "184"},
      {"ID": "510", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "184"},
      {"ID": "511", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "185"},
      {"ID": "512", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "185"},
      {"ID": "513", "OPTION": "Left", "QUESTIONID": "186"},
      {"ID": "514", "OPTION": "Center", "QUESTIONID": "186"},
      {"ID": "515", "OPTION": "Justify", "QUESTIONID": "186"},
      {"ID": "516", "OPTION": "Single", "QUESTIONID": "187"},
      {"ID": "517", "OPTION": "1.15", "QUESTIONID": "187"},
      {"ID": "518", "OPTION": "2.0", "QUESTIONID": "187"},
      {"ID": "519", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "188"},
      {"ID": "520", "OPTION": "Font", "QUESTIONID": "188"},
      {"ID": "521", "OPTION": "Home", "QUESTIONID": "188"},
      {"ID": "522", "OPTION": "Home", "QUESTIONID": "189"},
      {"ID": "523", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "189"},
      {"ID": "524", "OPTION": "Design", "QUESTIONID": "189"},
      {"ID": "525", "OPTION": "Sentence case", "QUESTIONID": "190"},
      {"ID": "526", "OPTION": "Lowercase", "QUESTIONID": "190"},
      {"ID": "527", "OPTION": "Toggle case", "QUESTIONID": "190"},
      {"ID": "528", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "191"},
      {"ID": "529", "OPTION": "Scratch", "QUESTIONID": "191"},
      {"ID": "530", "OPTION": "Programming", "QUESTIONID": "191"},
      {"ID": "531", "OPTION": "Program", "QUESTIONID": "191"},
      {"ID": "532", "OPTION": "Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "192"},
      {"ID": "533", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "192"},
      {"ID": "534", "OPTION": "Scratch", "QUESTIONID": "192"},
      {"ID": "535", "OPTION": "Programming", "QUESTIONID": "192"},
      {"ID": "536", "OPTION": "Program", "QUESTIONID": "193"},
      {"ID": "537", "OPTION": "Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "193"},
      {"ID": "538", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "193"},
      {"ID": "539", "OPTION": "Scratch", "QUESTIONID": "193"},
      {"ID": "540", "OPTION": "Programming", "QUESTIONID": "194"},
      {"ID": "541", "OPTION": "Program", "QUESTIONID": "194"},
      {"ID": "542", "OPTION": "Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "194"},
      {"ID": "543", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "194"},
      {"ID": "544", "OPTION": "Scratch", "QUESTIONID": "195"},
      {"ID": "545", "OPTION": "Programming", "QUESTIONID": "195"},
      {"ID": "546", "OPTION": "Program", "QUESTIONID": "195"},
      {"ID": "547", "OPTION": "Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "195"},
      {"ID": "548", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "196"},
      {"ID": "549", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "196"},
      {"ID": "550", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "197"},
      {"ID": "551", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "197"},
      {"ID": "552", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "198"},
      {"ID": "553", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "198"},
      {"ID": "554", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "199"},
      {"ID": "555", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "199"},
      {"ID": "556", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "200"},
      {"ID": "557", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "200"},
      {"ID": "558", "OPTION": "Sprites", "QUESTIONID": "201"},
      {"ID": "559", "OPTION": "Icons", "QUESTIONID": "201"},
      {"ID": "560", "OPTION": "Scripts", "QUESTIONID": "201"},
      {"ID": "561", "OPTION": "Scripts Area", "QUESTIONID": "202"},
      {"ID": "562", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "202"},
      {"ID": "563", "OPTION": "Blocks Palette", "QUESTIONID": "202"},
      {"ID": "564", "OPTION": "Pen Block", "QUESTIONID": "203"},
      {"ID": "565", "OPTION": "Motion Block", "QUESTIONID": "203"},
      {"ID": "566", "OPTION": "Both a and b", "QUESTIONID": "203"},
      {"ID": "567", "OPTION": "Pen", "QUESTIONID": "204"},
      {"ID": "568", "OPTION": "Motion", "QUESTIONID": "204"},
      {"ID": "569", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "204"},
      {"ID": "570", "OPTION": "Pen", "QUESTIONID": "205"},
      {"ID": "571", "OPTION": "CPU", "QUESTIONID": "205"},
      {"ID": "572", "OPTION": "RAM", "QUESTIONID": "205"},
      {"ID": "573", "OPTION": "Information", "QUESTIONID": "205"},
      {"ID": "574", "OPTION": "Information", "QUESTIONID": "206"},
      {"ID": "575", "OPTION": "Binary", "QUESTIONID": "206"},
      {"ID": "576", "OPTION": "Pen", "QUESTIONID": "206"},
      {"ID": "577", "OPTION": "CPU", "QUESTIONID": "206"},
      {"ID": "578", "OPTION": "RAM", "QUESTIONID": "207"},
      {"ID": "579", "OPTION": "Information", "QUESTIONID": "207"},
      {"ID": "580", "OPTION": "Binary", "QUESTIONID": "207"},
      {"ID": "581", "OPTION": "Pen", "QUESTIONID": "207"},
      {"ID": "582", "OPTION": "CPU", "QUESTIONID": "208"},
      {"ID": "583", "OPTION": "RAM", "QUESTIONID": "208"},
      {"ID": "584", "OPTION": "Pen", "QUESTIONID": "208"},
      {"ID": "585", "OPTION": "Information", "QUESTIONID": "208"},
      {"ID": "586", "OPTION": "Binary", "QUESTIONID": "209"},
      {"ID": "587", "OPTION": "Pen", "QUESTIONID": "209"},
      {"ID": "588", "OPTION": "CPU", "QUESTIONID": "209"},
      {"ID": "589", "OPTION": "RAM", "QUESTIONID": "209"},
      {"ID": "590", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "210"},
      {"ID": "591", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "210"},
      {"ID": "592", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "211"},
      {"ID": "593", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "211"},
      {"ID": "594", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "212"},
      {"ID": "595", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "212"},
      {"ID": "596", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "213"},
      {"ID": "597", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "213"},
      {"ID": "598", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "214"},
      {"ID": "599", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "214"},
      {"ID": "600", "OPTION": "RAM", "QUESTIONID": "215"},
      {"ID": "601", "OPTION": "ROM", "QUESTIONID": "215"},
      {"ID": "602", "OPTION": "Hard Disk", "QUESTIONID": "215"},
      {"ID": "603", "OPTION": "Flash Drive", "QUESTIONID": "216"},
      {"ID": "604", "OPTION": "CD", "QUESTIONID": "216"},
      {"ID": "605", "OPTION": "Multimedia Card", "QUESTIONID": "216"},
      {"ID": "606", "OPTION": "Main memory", "QUESTIONID": "217"},
      {"ID": "607", "OPTION": "Primary memory", "QUESTIONID": "217"},
      {"ID": "608", "OPTION": "Secondary memory", "QUESTIONID": "217"},
      {"ID": "609", "OPTION": "Bytes", "QUESTIONID": "218"},
      {"ID": "610", "OPTION": "Points", "QUESTIONID": "218"},
      {"ID": "611", "OPTION": "Pixels", "QUESTIONID": "218"},
      {"ID": "612", "OPTION": "CD", "QUESTIONID": "219"},
      {"ID": "613", "OPTION": "Pen Drive", "QUESTIONID": "219"},
      {"ID": "614", "OPTION": "Hard Disk", "QUESTIONID": "219"},
      {"ID": "615", "OPTION": "Quick Launch Bar", "QUESTIONID": "220"},
      {"ID": "616", "OPTION": "Application Icons", "QUESTIONID": "220"},
      {"ID": "617", "OPTION": "Personalize", "QUESTIONID": "220"},
      {"ID": "618", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "220"},
      {"ID": "619", "OPTION": "Notification", "QUESTIONID": "221"},
      {"ID": "620", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "221"},
      {"ID": "621", "OPTION": "Quick Launch Bar", "QUESTIONID": "221"},
      {"ID": "622", "OPTION": "Application Icons", "QUESTIONID": "221"},
      {"ID": "623", "OPTION": "Personalize", "QUESTIONID": "222"},
      {"ID": "624", "OPTION": "Notification", "QUESTIONID": "222"},
      {"ID": "625", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "222"},
      {"ID": "626", "OPTION": "Quick Launch Bar", "QUESTIONID": "222"},
      {"ID": "627", "OPTION": "Application Icons", "QUESTIONID": "223"},
      {"ID": "628", "OPTION": "Personalize", "QUESTIONID": "223"},
      {"ID": "629", "OPTION": "Notification", "QUESTIONID": "223"},
      {"ID": "630", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "223"},
      {"ID": "631", "OPTION": "Taskbar", "QUESTIONID": "224"},
      {"ID": "632", "OPTION": "Quick Launch Bar", "QUESTIONID": "224"},
      {"ID": "633", "OPTION": "Application Icons", "QUESTIONID": "224"},
      {"ID": "634", "OPTION": "Personalize", "QUESTIONID": "224"},
      {"ID": "635", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "225"},
      {"ID": "636", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "225"},
      {"ID": "637", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "226"},
      {"ID": "638", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "226"},
      {"ID": "639", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "227"},
      {"ID": "640", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "227"},
      {"ID": "641", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "228"},
      {"ID": "642", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "228"},
      {"ID": "643", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "229"},
      {"ID": "644", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "229"},
      {"ID": "645", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "230"},
      {"ID": "646", "OPTION": "Recycle Bin", "QUESTIONID": "230"},
      {"ID": "647", "OPTION": "Document", "QUESTIONID": "230"},
      {"ID": "648", "OPTION": "Jump Lists", "QUESTIONID": "231"},
      {"ID": "649", "OPTION": "Cascading Windows", "QUESTIONID": "231"},
      {"ID": "650", "OPTION": "Notification Area", "QUESTIONID": "231"},
      {"ID": "651", "OPTION": "Cascading windows", "QUESTIONID": "232"},
      {"ID": "652", "OPTION": "Multiple windows", "QUESTIONID": "232"},
      {"ID": "653", "OPTION": "Layered windows", "QUESTIONID": "232"},
      {"ID": "654", "OPTION": "Make transparency", "QUESTIONID": "233"},
      {"ID": "655", "OPTION": "Show transparency", "QUESTIONID": "233"},
      {"ID": "656", "OPTION": "Enable transparency", "QUESTIONID": "233"},
      {
        "ID": "657",
        "OPTION": "Geometrical User Interface",
        "QUESTIONID": "234"
      },
      {
        "ID": "658",
        "OPTION": "Graphical Unified Interface",
        "QUESTIONID": "234"
      },
      {"ID": "659", "OPTION": "Graphical User Interface", "QUESTIONID": "234"},
      {"ID": "660", "OPTION": "Internet", "QUESTIONID": "235"},
      {"ID": "661", "OPTION": "AI", "QUESTIONID": "235"},
      {"ID": "662", "OPTION": "Smartphone", "QUESTIONID": "235"},
      {"ID": "663", "OPTION": "Watch", "QUESTIONID": "235"},
      {"ID": "664", "OPTION": "Sensors", "QUESTIONID": "236"},
      {"ID": "665", "OPTION": "Internet", "QUESTIONID": "236"},
      {"ID": "666", "OPTION": "AI", "QUESTIONID": "236"},
      {"ID": "667", "OPTION": "Smartphone", "QUESTIONID": "236"},
      {"ID": "668", "OPTION": "Watch", "QUESTIONID": "237"},
      {"ID": "669", "OPTION": "Sensors", "QUESTIONID": "237"},
      {"ID": "670", "OPTION": "Internet", "QUESTIONID": "237"},
      {"ID": "671", "OPTION": "AI", "QUESTIONID": "237"},
      {"ID": "672", "OPTION": "AI", "QUESTIONID": "238"},
      {"ID": "673", "OPTION": "Smartphone", "QUESTIONID": "238"},
      {"ID": "674", "OPTION": "Watch", "QUESTIONID": "238"},
      {"ID": "675", "OPTION": "Sensors", "QUESTIONID": "238"},
      {"ID": "676", "OPTION": "Smartphone", "QUESTIONID": "239"},
      {"ID": "677", "OPTION": "Watch", "QUESTIONID": "239"},
      {"ID": "678", "OPTION": "Sensors", "QUESTIONID": "239"},
      {"ID": "679", "OPTION": "Internet", "QUESTIONID": "239"},
      {"ID": "680", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "240"},
      {"ID": "681", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "240"},
      {"ID": "682", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "241"},
      {"ID": "683", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "241"},
      {"ID": "684", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "242"},
      {"ID": "685", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "242"},
      {"ID": "686", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "243"},
      {"ID": "687", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "243"},
      {"ID": "688", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "244"},
      {"ID": "689", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "244"},
      {"ID": "690", "OPTION": "Environment", "QUESTIONID": "245"},
      {"ID": "691", "OPTION": "Sensors", "QUESTIONID": "245"},
      {"ID": "692", "OPTION": "Brakes", "QUESTIONID": "245"},
      {"ID": "693", "OPTION": "Make telephone calls", "QUESTIONID": "246"},
      {"ID": "694", "OPTION": "Surveillance cameras", "QUESTIONID": "246"},
      {
        "ID": "695",
        "OPTION": "Count the number of footsteps",
        "QUESTIONID": "246"
      },
      {"ID": "696", "OPTION": "Recording footage", "QUESTIONID": "247"},
      {"ID": "697", "OPTION": "Capturing image", "QUESTIONID": "247"},
      {"ID": "698", "OPTION": "Both a and b", "QUESTIONID": "247"},
      {"ID": "699", "OPTION": "OiT", "QUESTIONID": "248"},
      {"ID": "700", "OPTION": "ToI", "QUESTIONID": "248"},
      {"ID": "701", "OPTION": "IoT", "QUESTIONID": "248"},
      {"ID": "702", "OPTION": "Amazon Echo", "QUESTIONID": "249"},
      {"ID": "703", "OPTION": "Smart Home", "QUESTIONID": "249"},
      {"ID": "704", "OPTION": "Smart Watch", "QUESTIONID": "249"},
      {"ID": "705", "OPTION": "Smart Watch", "QUESTIONID": "250"},
      {"ID": "706", "OPTION": "Amazon Echo", "QUESTIONID": "250"},
      {"ID": "707", "OPTION": "Smart TV", "QUESTIONID": "250"},
      {"ID": "708", "OPTION": "0.5 inch", "QUESTIONID": "251"},
      {"ID": "709", "OPTION": "Margins", "QUESTIONID": "251"},
      {"ID": "710", "OPTION": "Double-click", "QUESTIONID": "251"},
      {"ID": "711", "OPTION": "1 inch", "QUESTIONID": "251"},
      {"ID": "712", "OPTION": "Header", "QUESTIONID": "252"},
      {"ID": "713", "OPTION": "0.5 inch", "QUESTIONID": "252"},
      {"ID": "714", "OPTION": "Margins", "QUESTIONID": "252"},
      {"ID": "715", "OPTION": "Double-click", "QUESTIONID": "252"},
      {"ID": "716", "OPTION": "1 inch", "QUESTIONID": "253"},
      {"ID": "717", "OPTION": "Header", "QUESTIONID": "253"},
      {"ID": "718", "OPTION": "0.5 inch", "QUESTIONID": "253"},
      {"ID": "719", "OPTION": "Margins", "QUESTIONID": "253"},
      {"ID": "720", "OPTION": "Double-click", "QUESTIONID": "254"},
      {"ID": "721", "OPTION": "1 inch", "QUESTIONID": "254"},
      {"ID": "722", "OPTION": "Header", "QUESTIONID": "254"},
      {"ID": "723", "OPTION": "0.5 inch", "QUESTIONID": "254"},
      {"ID": "724", "OPTION": "Margins", "QUESTIONID": "255"},
      {"ID": "725", "OPTION": "Double-click", "QUESTIONID": "255"},
      {"ID": "726", "OPTION": "0.5 inch", "QUESTIONID": "255"},
      {"ID": "727", "OPTION": "1 inch", "QUESTIONID": "255"},
      {"ID": "728", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "256"},
      {"ID": "729", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "256"},
      {"ID": "730", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "257"},
      {"ID": "731", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "257"},
      {"ID": "732", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "258"},
      {"ID": "733", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "258"},
      {"ID": "734", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "259"},
      {"ID": "735", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "259"},
      {"ID": "736", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "260"},
      {"ID": "737", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "260"},
      {"ID": "738", "OPTION": "Indentation", "QUESTIONID": "261"},
      {"ID": "739", "OPTION": "Page Orientation", "QUESTIONID": "261"},
      {"ID": "740", "OPTION": "Margin", "QUESTIONID": "261"},
      {"ID": "741", "OPTION": "Page Break", "QUESTIONID": "262"},
      {"ID": "742", "OPTION": "Footer", "QUESTIONID": "262"},
      {"ID": "743", "OPTION": "Superscript", "QUESTIONID": "262"},
      {"ID": "744", "OPTION": "Decrease indent", "QUESTIONID": "263"},
      {"ID": "745", "OPTION": "Increase indent", "QUESTIONID": "263"},
      {"ID": "746", "OPTION": "Spacing", "QUESTIONID": "263"},
      {"ID": "747", "OPTION": "Vertical ruler", "QUESTIONID": "264"},
      {"ID": "748", "OPTION": "Horizontal ruler", "QUESTIONID": "264"},
      {"ID": "749", "OPTION": "Tab stop", "QUESTIONID": "264"},
      {"ID": "750", "OPTION": "Landscape", "QUESTIONID": "265"},
      {"ID": "751", "OPTION": "Portrait", "QUESTIONID": "265"},
      {"ID": "752", "OPTION": "Vertical", "QUESTIONID": "265"},
      {"ID": "753", "OPTION": "WordArt", "QUESTIONID": "266"},
      {"ID": "754", "OPTION": "Illustrations", "QUESTIONID": "266"},
      {"ID": "755", "OPTION": "Match case", "QUESTIONID": "266"},
      {"ID": "756", "OPTION": "Shapes", "QUESTIONID": "266"},
      {"ID": "757", "OPTION": "Clip Art", "QUESTIONID": "267"},
      {"ID": "758", "OPTION": "WordArt", "QUESTIONID": "267"},
      {"ID": "759", "OPTION": "Illustrations", "QUESTIONID": "267"},
      {"ID": "760", "OPTION": "Match case", "QUESTIONID": "267"},
      {"ID": "761", "OPTION": "Shapes", "QUESTIONID": "268"},
      {"ID": "762", "OPTION": "Clip Art", "QUESTIONID": "268"},
      {"ID": "763", "OPTION": "WordArt", "QUESTIONID": "268"},
      {"ID": "764", "OPTION": "Illustrations", "QUESTIONID": "268"},
      {"ID": "765", "OPTION": "Match case", "QUESTIONID": "269"},
      {"ID": "766", "OPTION": "Shapes", "QUESTIONID": "269"},
      {"ID": "767", "OPTION": "Clip Art", "QUESTIONID": "269"},
      {"ID": "768", "OPTION": "WordArt", "QUESTIONID": "269"},
      {"ID": "769", "OPTION": "Illustrations", "QUESTIONID": "270"},
      {"ID": "770", "OPTION": "Match case", "QUESTIONID": "270"},
      {"ID": "771", "OPTION": "Shapes", "QUESTIONID": "270"},
      {"ID": "772", "OPTION": "Clip Art", "QUESTIONID": "270"},
      {"ID": "773", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "271"},
      {"ID": "774", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "271"},
      {"ID": "775", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "272"},
      {"ID": "776", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "272"},
      {"ID": "777", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "273"},
      {"ID": "778", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "273"},
      {"ID": "779", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "274"},
      {"ID": "780", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "274"},
      {"ID": "781", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "275"},
      {"ID": "782", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "275"},
      {"ID": "783", "OPTION": "Ctrl + F", "QUESTIONID": "276"},
      {"ID": "784", "OPTION": "Ctrl + H", "QUESTIONID": "276"},
      {"ID": "785", "OPTION": "Ctrl + S", "QUESTIONID": "276"},
      {"ID": "786", "OPTION": "Home", "QUESTIONID": "277"},
      {"ID": "787", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "277"},
      {"ID": "788", "OPTION": "Format", "QUESTIONID": "277"},
      {"ID": "789", "OPTION": "Format", "QUESTIONID": "278"},
      {"ID": "790", "OPTION": "Home", "QUESTIONID": "278"},
      {"ID": "791", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "278"},
      {"ID": "792", "OPTION": "Ctrl + F", "QUESTIONID": "279"},
      {"ID": "793", "OPTION": "Ctrl + H", "QUESTIONID": "279"},
      {"ID": "794", "OPTION": "Ctrl + S", "QUESTIONID": "279"},
      {"ID": "795", "OPTION": "Paragraph", "QUESTIONID": "280"},
      {"ID": "796", "OPTION": "Text", "QUESTIONID": "280"},
      {"ID": "797", "OPTION": "Font", "QUESTIONID": "280"},
      {"ID": "798", "OPTION": "Stop", "QUESTIONID": "281"},
      {"ID": "799", "OPTION": "play sound ( ) until done", "QUESTIONID": "281"},
      {"ID": "800", "OPTION": "say ( )", "QUESTIONID": "281"},
      {"ID": "801", "OPTION": "Cat", "QUESTIONID": "281"},
      {"ID": "802", "OPTION": "wait ( ) secs", "QUESTIONID": "282"},
      {"ID": "803", "OPTION": "Stop", "QUESTIONID": "282"},
      {"ID": "804", "OPTION": "play sound ( ) until done", "QUESTIONID": "282"},
      {"ID": "805", "OPTION": "say ( )", "QUESTIONID": "282"},
      {"ID": "806", "OPTION": "Cat", "QUESTIONID": "283"},
      {"ID": "807", "OPTION": "wait ( ) secs", "QUESTIONID": "283"},
      {"ID": "808", "OPTION": "Stop", "QUESTIONID": "283"},
      {"ID": "809", "OPTION": "play sound ( ) until done", "QUESTIONID": "283"},
      {"ID": "810", "OPTION": "say ( )", "QUESTIONID": "284"},
      {"ID": "811", "OPTION": "Cat", "QUESTIONID": "284"},
      {"ID": "812", "OPTION": "wait ( ) secs", "QUESTIONID": "284"},
      {"ID": "813", "OPTION": "Stop", "QUESTIONID": "284"},
      {"ID": "814", "OPTION": "play sound ( ) until done", "QUESTIONID": "285"},
      {"ID": "815", "OPTION": "say ( )", "QUESTIONID": "285"},
      {"ID": "816", "OPTION": "Cat", "QUESTIONID": "285"},
      {"ID": "817", "OPTION": "wait ( ) secs", "QUESTIONID": "285"},
      {"ID": "818", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "286"},
      {"ID": "819", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "286"},
      {"ID": "820", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "287"},
      {"ID": "821", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "287"},
      {"ID": "822", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "288"},
      {"ID": "823", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "288"},
      {"ID": "824", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "289"},
      {"ID": "825", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "289"},
      {"ID": "826", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "290"},
      {"ID": "827", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "290"},
      {"ID": "828", "OPTION": "next costume", "QUESTIONID": "291"},
      {"ID": "829", "OPTION": "say ( )", "QUESTIONID": "292"},
      {"ID": "830", "OPTION": "Choose a costume", "QUESTIONID": "293"},
      {"ID": "831", "OPTION": "wait ( ) seconds", "QUESTIONID": "294"},
      {"ID": "832", "OPTION": "forever", "QUESTIONID": "295"},
      {"ID": "833", "OPTION": "Looks", "QUESTIONID": "296"},
      {"ID": "834", "OPTION": "Sound", "QUESTIONID": "296"},
      {"ID": "835", "OPTION": "Control", "QUESTIONID": "296"},
      {"ID": "836", "OPTION": "Costumes", "QUESTIONID": "297"},
      {"ID": "837", "OPTION": "Looks", "QUESTIONID": "297"},
      {"ID": "838", "OPTION": "Events", "QUESTIONID": "297"},
      {"ID": "839", "OPTION": "Cloud", "QUESTIONID": "298"},
      {"ID": "840", "OPTION": "Bubble", "QUESTIONID": "298"},
      {"ID": "841", "OPTION": "Circle", "QUESTIONID": "298"},
      {"ID": "842", "OPTION": "Top", "QUESTIONID": "299"},
      {"ID": "843", "OPTION": "Bottom", "QUESTIONID": "299"},
      {"ID": "844", "OPTION": "Left", "QUESTIONID": "299"},
      {"ID": "845", "OPTION": "Net Surfing", "QUESTIONID": "300"},
      {"ID": "846", "OPTION": "Search Engine", "QUESTIONID": "300"},
      {"ID": "847", "OPTION": "Internet", "QUESTIONID": "300"},
      {"ID": "848", "OPTION": "URL", "QUESTIONID": "300"},
      {"ID": "849", "OPTION": "URL", "QUESTIONID": "301"},
      {"ID": "850", "OPTION": "Web page", "QUESTIONID": "301"},
      {"ID": "851", "OPTION": "ISP", "QUESTIONID": "301"},
      {"ID": "852", "OPTION": "Net Surfing", "QUESTIONID": "301"},
      {"ID": "853", "OPTION": "Search Engine", "QUESTIONID": "302"},
      {"ID": "854", "OPTION": "Internet", "QUESTIONID": "302"},
      {"ID": "855", "OPTION": "URL", "QUESTIONID": "302"},
      {"ID": "856", "OPTION": "ISP", "QUESTIONID": "302"},
      {"ID": "857", "OPTION": "Web page", "QUESTIONID": "303"},
      {"ID": "858", "OPTION": "ISP", "QUESTIONID": "303"},
      {"ID": "859", "OPTION": "Net Surfing", "QUESTIONID": "303"},
      {"ID": "860", "OPTION": "Search Engine", "QUESTIONID": "303"},
      {"ID": "861", "OPTION": "Internet", "QUESTIONID": "304"},
      {"ID": "862", "OPTION": "URL", "QUESTIONID": "304"},
      {"ID": "863", "OPTION": "Web page", "QUESTIONID": "304"},
      {"ID": "864", "OPTION": "Net Surfing", "QUESTIONID": "304"},
      {"ID": "865", "OPTION": "ISP", "QUESTIONID": "305"},
      {"ID": "866", "OPTION": "Net Surfing", "QUESTIONID": "305"},
      {"ID": "867", "OPTION": "Search Engine", "QUESTIONID": "305"},
      {"ID": "868", "OPTION": "Web page", "QUESTIONID": "305"},
      {"ID": "869", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "306"},
      {"ID": "870", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "306"},
      {"ID": "871", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "307"},
      {"ID": "872", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "307"},
      {"ID": "873", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "308"},
      {"ID": "874", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "308"},
      {"ID": "875", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "309"},
      {"ID": "876", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "309"},
      {"ID": "877", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "310"},
      {"ID": "878", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "310"},
      {"ID": "879", "OPTION": "Home Page", "QUESTIONID": "311"},
      {"ID": "880", "OPTION": "Welcome Page", "QUESTIONID": "311"},
      {"ID": "881", "OPTION": "Starting Page", "QUESTIONID": "311"},
      {"ID": "882", "OPTION": "Bing", "QUESTIONID": "312"},
      {"ID": "883", "OPTION": "Google Chrome", "QUESTIONID": "312"},
      {"ID": "884", "OPTION": "Google", "QUESTIONID": "312"},
      {"ID": "885", "OPTION": "Web Browser", "QUESTIONID": "313"},
      {"ID": "886", "OPTION": "URL", "QUESTIONID": "313"},
      {"ID": "887", "OPTION": "Antivirus", "QUESTIONID": "313"},
      {"ID": "888", "OPTION": "Hand", "QUESTIONID": "314"},
      {"ID": "889", "OPTION": "Hour Glass", "QUESTIONID": "314"},
      {"ID": "890", "OPTION": "Cross", "QUESTIONID": "314"},
      {"ID": "891", "OPTION": "ISP", "QUESTIONID": "315"},
      {"ID": "892", "OPTION": "Google", "QUESTIONID": "315"},
      {"ID": "893", "OPTION": "Mozilla Firefox", "QUESTIONID": "315"},
      {"ID": "894", "OPTION": "Recent", "QUESTIONID": "316"},
      {"ID": "895", "OPTION": "Latest", "QUESTIONID": "316"},
      {"ID": "896", "OPTION": "History", "QUESTIONID": "316"},
      {"ID": "897", "OPTION": "Utility, Interpreter", "QUESTIONID": "317"},
      {"ID": "898", "OPTION": "Application, System", "QUESTIONID": "317"},
      {"ID": "899", "OPTION": "Interpreter, Utility", "QUESTIONID": "317"},
      {"ID": "900", "OPTION": "System, Application", "QUESTIONID": "317"},
      {"ID": "901", "OPTION": "Interpreter", "QUESTIONID": "318"},
      {"ID": "902", "OPTION": "Operating System", "QUESTIONID": "318"},
      {"ID": "903", "OPTION": "Presentation", "QUESTIONID": "318"},
      {"ID": "904", "OPTION": "Utility", "QUESTIONID": "318"},
      {"ID": "905", "OPTION": "Utility", "QUESTIONID": "319"},
      {"ID": "906", "OPTION": "Interpreter", "QUESTIONID": "319"},
      {"ID": "907", "OPTION": "Operating System", "QUESTIONID": "319"},
      {"ID": "908", "OPTION": "Presentation", "QUESTIONID": "319"},
      {"ID": "909", "OPTION": "Presentation", "QUESTIONID": "320"},
      {"ID": "910", "OPTION": "Utility", "QUESTIONID": "320"},
      {"ID": "911", "OPTION": "Interpreter", "QUESTIONID": "320"},
      {"ID": "912", "OPTION": "Operating System", "QUESTIONID": "320"},
      {"ID": "913", "OPTION": "Operating System", "QUESTIONID": "321"},
      {"ID": "914", "OPTION": "Presentation", "QUESTIONID": "321"},
      {"ID": "915", "OPTION": "Utility", "QUESTIONID": "321"},
      {"ID": "916", "OPTION": "Interpreter", "QUESTIONID": "321"},
      {"ID": "917", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "322"},
      {"ID": "918", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "322"},
      {"ID": "919", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "323"},
      {"ID": "920", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "323"},
      {"ID": "921", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "324"},
      {"ID": "922", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "324"},
      {"ID": "923", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "325"},
      {"ID": "924", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "325"},
      {"ID": "925", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "326"},
      {"ID": "926", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "326"},
      {"ID": "927", "OPTION": "Devices", "QUESTIONID": "327"},
      {"ID": "928", "OPTION": "Network", "QUESTIONID": "327"},
      {"ID": "929", "OPTION": "File Manager", "QUESTIONID": "327"},
      {"ID": "930", "OPTION": "Computer", "QUESTIONID": "328"},
      {"ID": "931", "OPTION": "Interpreter", "QUESTIONID": "328"},
      {"ID": "932", "OPTION": "Assembler", "QUESTIONID": "328"},
      {"ID": "933", "OPTION": "Spreadsheet", "QUESTIONID": "329"},
      {"ID": "934", "OPTION": "Word Processor", "QUESTIONID": "329"},
      {"ID": "935", "OPTION": "DTP", "QUESTIONID": "329"},
      {"ID": "936", "OPTION": "Norton", "QUESTIONID": "330"},
      {"ID": "937", "OPTION": "Winzip", "QUESTIONID": "330"},
      {"ID": "938", "OPTION": "Both a and b", "QUESTIONID": "330"},
      {"ID": "939", "OPTION": "Special purpose", "QUESTIONID": "331"},
      {"ID": "940", "OPTION": "General purpose", "QUESTIONID": "331"},
      {"ID": "941", "OPTION": "System", "QUESTIONID": "331"},
      {"ID": "942", "OPTION": "Source", "QUESTIONID": "332"},
      {"ID": "943", "OPTION": "Show Desktop", "QUESTIONID": "332"},
      {"ID": "944", "OPTION": "Recycle Bin", "QUESTIONID": "332"},
      {"ID": "945", "OPTION": "Search Box", "QUESTIONID": "332"},
      {"ID": "946", "OPTION": "Windows Explorer", "QUESTIONID": "333"},
      {"ID": "947", "OPTION": "Source", "QUESTIONID": "333"},
      {"ID": "948", "OPTION": "Show Desktop", "QUESTIONID": "333"},
      {"ID": "949", "OPTION": "Recycle Bin", "QUESTIONID": "333"},
      {"ID": "950", "OPTION": "Search Box", "QUESTIONID": "334"},
      {"ID": "951", "OPTION": "Windows Explorer", "QUESTIONID": "334"},
      {"ID": "952", "OPTION": "Source", "QUESTIONID": "334"},
      {"ID": "953", "OPTION": "Show Desktop", "QUESTIONID": "334"},
      {"ID": "954", "OPTION": "Recycle Bin", "QUESTIONID": "335"},
      {"ID": "955", "OPTION": "Search Box", "QUESTIONID": "335"},
      {"ID": "956", "OPTION": "Windows Explorer", "QUESTIONID": "335"},
      {"ID": "957", "OPTION": "Source", "QUESTIONID": "335"},
      {"ID": "958", "OPTION": "Show Desktop", "QUESTIONID": "336"},
      {"ID": "959", "OPTION": "Recycle Bin", "QUESTIONID": "336"},
      {"ID": "960", "OPTION": "Search Box", "QUESTIONID": "336"},
      {"ID": "961", "OPTION": "Windows Explorer", "QUESTIONID": "336"},
      {"ID": "962", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "337"},
      {"ID": "963", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "337"},
      {"ID": "964", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "338"},
      {"ID": "965", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "338"},
      {"ID": "966", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "339"},
      {"ID": "967", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "339"},
      {"ID": "968", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "340"},
      {"ID": "969", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "340"},
      {"ID": "970", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "341"},
      {"ID": "971", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "341"},
      {"ID": "972", "OPTION": "Shift", "QUESTIONID": "342"},
      {"ID": "973", "OPTION": "Ctrl", "QUESTIONID": "342"},
      {"ID": "974", "OPTION": "Alt", "QUESTIONID": "342"},
      {"ID": "975", "OPTION": "Snap", "QUESTIONID": "343"},
      {"ID": "976", "OPTION": "Shake", "QUESTIONID": "343"},
      {"ID": "977", "OPTION": "Jump List", "QUESTIONID": "343"},
      {"ID": "978", "OPTION": "Search Box", "QUESTIONID": "344"},
      {"ID": "979", "OPTION": "Explore Box", "QUESTIONID": "344"},
      {"ID": "980", "OPTION": "Locate Box", "QUESTIONID": "344"},
      {"ID": "981", "OPTION": "Aero Flip 3D", "QUESTIONID": "345"},
      {"ID": "982", "OPTION": "Aero Peek", "QUESTIONID": "345"},
      {"ID": "983", "OPTION": "Snap", "QUESTIONID": "345"},
      {"ID": "984", "OPTION": "Snap", "QUESTIONID": "346"},
      {"ID": "985", "OPTION": "Aero Flip 3D", "QUESTIONID": "346"},
      {"ID": "986", "OPTION": "Jump List", "QUESTIONID": "346"},
      {
        "ID": "987",
        "OPTION": "Natural Language Processing",
        "QUESTIONID": "347"
      },
      {"ID": "988", "OPTION": "Computer Vision", "QUESTIONID": "347"},
      {"ID": "989", "OPTION": "Google Maps", "QUESTIONID": "347"},
      {"ID": "990", "OPTION": "Algorithm", "QUESTIONID": "347"},
      {"ID": "991", "OPTION": "Algorithm", "QUESTIONID": "348"},
      {
        "ID": "992",
        "OPTION": "Natural Language Processing",
        "QUESTIONID": "348"
      },
      {"ID": "993", "OPTION": "Computer Vision", "QUESTIONID": "348"},
      {"ID": "994", "OPTION": "Google Maps", "QUESTIONID": "348"},
      {"ID": "995", "OPTION": "Google Maps", "QUESTIONID": "349"},
      {"ID": "996", "OPTION": "Algorithm", "QUESTIONID": "349"},
      {
        "ID": "997",
        "OPTION": "Natural Language Processing",
        "QUESTIONID": "349"
      },
      {"ID": "998", "OPTION": "Computer Vision", "QUESTIONID": "349"},
      {"ID": "999", "OPTION": "Computer Vision", "QUESTIONID": "350"},
      {"ID": "1000", "OPTION": "Google Maps", "QUESTIONID": "350"},
      {"ID": "1001", "OPTION": "Algorithm", "QUESTIONID": "350"},
      {
        "ID": "1002",
        "OPTION": "Natural Language Processing",
        "QUESTIONID": "350"
      },
      {"ID": "1003", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "351"},
      {"ID": "1004", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "351"},
      {"ID": "1005", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "352"},
      {"ID": "1006", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "352"},
      {"ID": "1007", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "353"},
      {"ID": "1008", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "353"},
      {"ID": "1009", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "354"},
      {"ID": "1010", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "354"},
      {"ID": "1011", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "355"},
      {"ID": "1012", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "355"},
      {"ID": "1013", "OPTION": "Layout", "QUESTIONID": "356"},
      {"ID": "1014", "OPTION": "Slides", "QUESTIONID": "356"},
      {"ID": "1015", "OPTION": "Normal", "QUESTIONID": "356"},
      {"ID": "1016", "OPTION": ".pptx", "QUESTIONID": "356"},
      {"ID": "1017", "OPTION": "Slide Sorter", "QUESTIONID": "357"},
      {"ID": "1018", "OPTION": "Layout", "QUESTIONID": "357"},
      {"ID": "1019", "OPTION": "Slides", "QUESTIONID": "357"},
      {"ID": "1020", "OPTION": "Normal", "QUESTIONID": "357"},
      {"ID": "1021", "OPTION": ".pptx", "QUESTIONID": "358"},
      {"ID": "1022", "OPTION": "Slide Sorter", "QUESTIONID": "358"},
      {"ID": "1023", "OPTION": "Layout", "QUESTIONID": "358"},
      {"ID": "1024", "OPTION": "Slides", "QUESTIONID": "358"},
      {"ID": "1025", "OPTION": "Normal", "QUESTIONID": "359"},
      {"ID": "1026", "OPTION": ".pptx", "QUESTIONID": "359"},
      {"ID": "1027", "OPTION": "Slide Sorter", "QUESTIONID": "359"},
      {"ID": "1028", "OPTION": "Layout", "QUESTIONID": "359"},
      {"ID": "1029", "OPTION": "Slides", "QUESTIONID": "360"},
      {"ID": "1030", "OPTION": "Normal", "QUESTIONID": "360"},
      {"ID": "1031", "OPTION": ".pptx", "QUESTIONID": "360"},
      {"ID": "1032", "OPTION": "Slide Sorter", "QUESTIONID": "360"},
      {"ID": "1033", "OPTION": "View", "QUESTIONID": "361"},
      {"ID": "1034", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "361"},
      {"ID": "1035", "OPTION": "Home", "QUESTIONID": "361"},
      {"ID": "1036", "OPTION": "F9", "QUESTIONID": "362"},
      {"ID": "1037", "OPTION": "F5", "QUESTIONID": "362"},
      {"ID": "1038", "OPTION": "F10", "QUESTIONID": "362"},
      {"ID": "1039", "OPTION": "Normal View", "QUESTIONID": "363"},
      {"ID": "1040", "OPTION": "Slide Sorter View", "QUESTIONID": "363"},
      {"ID": "1041", "OPTION": "Slide Show View", "QUESTIONID": "363"},
      {"ID": "1042", "OPTION": "Placeholder", "QUESTIONID": "364"},
      {"ID": "1043", "OPTION": "Slide", "QUESTIONID": "364"},
      {"ID": "1044", "OPTION": "Slide Pane", "QUESTIONID": "364"},
      {"ID": "1045", "OPTION": "Slide Show", "QUESTIONID": "365"},
      {"ID": "1046", "OPTION": "Slide Sorter", "QUESTIONID": "365"},
      {"ID": "1047", "OPTION": "Outline", "QUESTIONID": "365"},
      {"ID": "1048", "OPTION": "Ctrl + N", "QUESTIONID": "366"},
      {"ID": "1049", "OPTION": "Ctrl + O", "QUESTIONID": "366"},
      {"ID": "1050", "OPTION": "Ctrl + S", "QUESTIONID": "366"},
      {"ID": "1051", "OPTION": "Placeholders", "QUESTIONID": "367"},
      {"ID": "1052", "OPTION": "SmartArt", "QUESTIONID": "368"},
      {"ID": "1053", "OPTION": "Notes Page View", "QUESTIONID": "369"},
      {"ID": "1054", "OPTION": "Templates", "QUESTIONID": "370"},
      {"ID": "1055", "OPTION": "Rotation", "QUESTIONID": "371"},
      {"ID": "1056", "OPTION": "Slide Layout", "QUESTIONID": "371"},
      {"ID": "1057", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "371"},
      {"ID": "1058", "OPTION": "WordArt", "QUESTIONID": "371"},
      {"ID": "1059", "OPTION": "Text Box", "QUESTIONID": "372"},
      {"ID": "1060", "OPTION": "Rotation", "QUESTIONID": "372"},
      {"ID": "1061", "OPTION": "Slide Layout", "QUESTIONID": "372"},
      {"ID": "1062", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "372"},
      {"ID": "1063", "OPTION": "WordArt", "QUESTIONID": "373"},
      {"ID": "1064", "OPTION": "Text Box", "QUESTIONID": "373"},
      {"ID": "1065", "OPTION": "Rotation", "QUESTIONID": "373"},
      {"ID": "1066", "OPTION": "Slide Layout", "QUESTIONID": "373"},
      {"ID": "1067", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "374"},
      {"ID": "1068", "OPTION": "WordArt", "QUESTIONID": "374"},
      {"ID": "1069", "OPTION": "Text Box", "QUESTIONID": "374"},
      {"ID": "1070", "OPTION": "Rotation", "QUESTIONID": "374"},
      {"ID": "1071", "OPTION": "Slide Layout", "QUESTIONID": "375"},
      {"ID": "1072", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "375"},
      {"ID": "1073", "OPTION": "Rotation", "QUESTIONID": "375"},
      {"ID": "1074", "OPTION": "WordArt", "QUESTIONID": "375"},
      {"ID": "1075", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "376"},
      {"ID": "1076", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "376"},
      {"ID": "1077", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "377"},
      {"ID": "1078", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "377"},
      {"ID": "1079", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "378"},
      {"ID": "1080", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "378"},
      {"ID": "1081", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "379"},
      {"ID": "1082", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "379"},
      {"ID": "1083", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "380"},
      {"ID": "1084", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "380"},
      {"ID": "1085", "OPTION": "Slide Show", "QUESTIONID": "381"},
      {"ID": "1086", "OPTION": "Home", "QUESTIONID": "381"},
      {"ID": "1087", "OPTION": "View", "QUESTIONID": "381"},
      {"ID": "1088", "OPTION": "View", "QUESTIONID": "382"},
      {"ID": "1089", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "382"},
      {"ID": "1090", "OPTION": "Home", "QUESTIONID": "382"},
      {"ID": "1091", "OPTION": "Home", "QUESTIONID": "383"},
      {"ID": "1092", "OPTION": "Insert", "QUESTIONID": "383"},
      {"ID": "1093", "OPTION": "Design", "QUESTIONID": "383"},
      {"ID": "1094", "OPTION": "Rotate", "QUESTIONID": "384"},
      {"ID": "1095", "OPTION": "Selection Pane", "QUESTIONID": "384"},
      {"ID": "1096", "OPTION": "Shape Effects", "QUESTIONID": "384"},
      {"ID": "1097", "OPTION": "Style", "QUESTIONID": "385"},
      {"ID": "1098", "OPTION": "Rotating", "QUESTIONID": "385"},
      {"ID": "1099", "OPTION": "Resizing", "QUESTIONID": "385"},
      {"ID": "1100", "OPTION": "Normal View", "QUESTIONID": "386"},
      {"ID": "1101", "OPTION": "Shapes Button", "QUESTIONID": "387"},
      {"ID": "1102", "OPTION": "Ctrl Key", "QUESTIONID": "388"},
      {"ID": "1103", "OPTION": "Flipping", "QUESTIONID": "389"},
      {"ID": "1104", "OPTION": "Scripts Area", "QUESTIONID": "390"},
      {"ID": "1105", "OPTION": "Choose a Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "390"},
      {"ID": "1106", "OPTION": "Add Extension", "QUESTIONID": "390"},
      {"ID": "1107", "OPTION": "Origin", "QUESTIONID": "390"},
      {"ID": "1108", "OPTION": "Origin", "QUESTIONID": "391"},
      {"ID": "1109", "OPTION": "Music", "QUESTIONID": "391"},
      {"ID": "1110", "OPTION": "Scripts Area", "QUESTIONID": "391"},
      {"ID": "1111", "OPTION": "Choose a Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "391"},
      {"ID": "1112", "OPTION": "Add Extension", "QUESTIONID": "392"},
      {"ID": "1113", "OPTION": "Origin", "QUESTIONID": "392"},
      {"ID": "1114", "OPTION": "Music", "QUESTIONID": "392"},
      {"ID": "1115", "OPTION": "Scripts Area", "QUESTIONID": "392"},
      {"ID": "1116", "OPTION": "Choose a Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "393"},
      {"ID": "1117", "OPTION": "Add Extension", "QUESTIONID": "393"},
      {"ID": "1118", "OPTION": "Origin", "QUESTIONID": "393"},
      {"ID": "1119", "OPTION": "Music", "QUESTIONID": "393"},
      {"ID": "1120", "OPTION": "Music", "QUESTIONID": "394"},
      {"ID": "1121", "OPTION": "Scripts Area", "QUESTIONID": "394"},
      {"ID": "1122", "OPTION": "Choose a Sprite", "QUESTIONID": "394"},
      {"ID": "1123", "OPTION": "Add Extension", "QUESTIONID": "394"},
      {"ID": "1124", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "395"},
      {"ID": "1125", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "395"},
      {"ID": "1126", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "396"},
      {"ID": "1127", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "396"},
      {"ID": "1128", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "397"},
      {"ID": "1129", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "397"},
      {"ID": "1130", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "398"},
      {"ID": "1131", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "398"},
      {"ID": "1132", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "399"},
      {"ID": "1133", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "399"},
      {"ID": "1134", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "400"},
      {"ID": "1135", "OPTION": "Blocks Palette", "QUESTIONID": "400"},
      {"ID": "1136", "OPTION": "Backdrop", "QUESTIONID": "400"},
      {"ID": "1137", "OPTION": "Blocks", "QUESTIONID": "401"},
      {"ID": "1138", "OPTION": "Script", "QUESTIONID": "401"},
      {"ID": "1139", "OPTION": "Stage", "QUESTIONID": "401"},
      {"ID": "1140", "OPTION": "Add Extension", "QUESTIONID": "402"},
      {"ID": "1141", "OPTION": "Insert Extension", "QUESTIONID": "402"},
      {"ID": "1142", "OPTION": "Extension", "QUESTIONID": "402"},
      {"ID": "1143", "OPTION": "Motion", "QUESTIONID": "403"},
      {"ID": "1144", "OPTION": "Music", "QUESTIONID": "403"},
      {"ID": "1145", "OPTION": "Looks", "QUESTIONID": "403"},
      {"ID": "1146", "OPTION": "Internet TV", "QUESTIONID": "404"},
      {"ID": "1147", "OPTION": "Online Chat", "QUESTIONID": "404"},
      {"ID": "1148", "OPTION": "Compose", "QUESTIONID": "404"},
      {"ID": "1149", "OPTION": "E-learning", "QUESTIONID": "404"},
      {"ID": "1150", "OPTION": "E-learning", "QUESTIONID": "405"},
      {"ID": "1151", "OPTION": "Video Conference", "QUESTIONID": "405"},
      {"ID": "1152", "OPTION": "Internet TV", "QUESTIONID": "405"},
      {"ID": "1153", "OPTION": "Online Chat", "QUESTIONID": "405"},
      {"ID": "1154", "OPTION": "Compose", "QUESTIONID": "406"},
      {"ID": "1155", "OPTION": "E-learning", "QUESTIONID": "406"},
      {"ID": "1156", "OPTION": "Video Conference", "QUESTIONID": "406"},
      {"ID": "1157", "OPTION": "Internet TV", "QUESTIONID": "406"},
      {"ID": "1158", "OPTION": "Online Chat", "QUESTIONID": "407"},
      {"ID": "1159", "OPTION": "Compose", "QUESTIONID": "407"},
      {"ID": "1160", "OPTION": "E-learning", "QUESTIONID": "407"},
      {"ID": "1161", "OPTION": "Video Conference", "QUESTIONID": "407"},
      {"ID": "1162", "OPTION": "Video Conference", "QUESTIONID": "408"},
      {"ID": "1163", "OPTION": "Internet TV", "QUESTIONID": "408"},
      {"ID": "1164", "OPTION": "Online Chat", "QUESTIONID": "408"},
      {"ID": "1165", "OPTION": "Compose", "QUESTIONID": "408"},
      {"ID": "1166", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "409"},
      {"ID": "1167", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "409"},
      {"ID": "1168", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "410"},
      {"ID": "1169", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "410"},
      {"ID": "1170", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "411"},
      {"ID": "1171", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "411"},
      {"ID": "1172", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "412"},
      {"ID": "1173", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "412"},
      {"ID": "1174", "OPTION": "True", "QUESTIONID": "413"},
      {"ID": "1175", "OPTION": "False", "QUESTIONID": "413"},
      {"ID": "1176", "OPTION": "Bcc", "QUESTIONID": "414"},
      {"ID": "1177", "OPTION": "Cc", "QUESTIONID": "414"},
      {"ID": "1178", "OPTION": "None of these", "QUESTIONID": "414"},
      {"ID": "1179", "OPTION": "Social Media", "QUESTIONID": "415"},
      {"ID": "1180", "OPTION": "Social Meeting", "QUESTIONID": "415"},
      {"ID": "1181", "OPTION": "Multi Media", "QUESTIONID": "415"},
      {"ID": "1182", "OPTION": "#", "QUESTIONID": "416"},
      {"ID": "1183", "OPTION": "*", "QUESTIONID": "416"},
      {"ID": "1184", "OPTION": "@", "QUESTIONID": "416"},
      {"ID": "1185", "OPTION": "Scissors", "QUESTIONID": "417"},
      {"ID": "1186", "OPTION": "Paper clip", "QUESTIONID": "417"},
      {"ID": "1187", "OPTION": "All pin", "QUESTIONID": "417"}
    ],
    "QUESTION_MASTER": [
      {
        "ID": "1",
        "QUESTION": "A ………………………… shows all the work done on a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Monitor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "2",
        "QUESTION": "The ………………………… is known as the brain of a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CPU",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "3",
        "QUESTION": "A ………………………… has many keys.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Keyboard",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "4",
        "QUESTION": "A …………………………… has two buttons and a scroll wheel.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Mouse",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "5",
        "QUESTION": "A ………………………………… looks like a TV.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Monitor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "6",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can type letters and numbers using the ………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Keyboard",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "7",
        "QUESTION": "A ………………………………… is used to draw and colour pictures.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Mouse",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "8",
        "QUESTION":
            "The CPU helps a …………………………………work according to the given instructions.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Computer",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "1",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "9",
        "QUESTION": "A mouse has ………………………… buttons and a scrolling wheel.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Two",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "10",
        "QUESTION": "………………………… means pressing the right mouse button once.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Right-click",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "11",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………… on a laptop does the same job as the mouse of a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Touchpad",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "12",
        "QUESTION": "A mouse is kept on a ………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Mouse Pad",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "13",
        "QUESTION": "A mouse is used to move the ………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Mouse Pointer",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "14",
        "QUESTION": "………………………………… opens an item.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Double-clicking",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "15",
        "QUESTION": "Clicking the left button once is called a double-click.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "16",
        "QUESTION":
            "A scroll wheel is placed in between the left and right mouse buttons.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "17",
        "QUESTION": "A mouse pointer moves when you move the mouse.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "18",
        "QUESTION": "Double-clicking the right button opens an item.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "19",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which mouse action is used to move an item from one place to another?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "20",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which mouse button do you press to perform a click and a double-click?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "2",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "21",
        "QUESTION": "There are ………………………… number keys on a keyboard.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "10",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "22",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………… key is used to add blank spaces between words.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "23",
        "QUESTION": "The ………………………… keys are used to type sentences.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Alphabet",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "24",
        "QUESTION": "There are 26 ………………………………… keys on the keyboard.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Alphabet",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "25",
        "QUESTION": "A ………………………………… is a small blinking line on the monitor.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "26",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………………… key is used to move the cursor to the next line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "3",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "27",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………………… button is used to exit the Paint application.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Close",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "28",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………………… tool is used to fill colour in closed shapes.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Fill with color",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "29",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can select the Rectangle tool from ………………………………… group.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Shapes",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "30",
        "QUESTION": "You can draw and colour shapes in Paint.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "31",
        "QUESTION": "To draw an oval, you need to hold down the Shift key.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "32",
        "QUESTION": "You can draw a square using the Rectangle tool.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "4",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "33",
        "QUESTION": "A computer works on the ………………………… given by you.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Data",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "34",
        "QUESTION": "You can keep ………………………… in the refrigerator.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Water",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "35",
        "QUESTION":
            "The places where you store your things are called ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Storage Places",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "36",
        "QUESTION":
            "The words and numbers that you enter into a computer are called ………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Data",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "37",
        "QUESTION": "A ………………………………… is a device to store data on a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CD",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "38",
        "QUESTION": "A …………………………………… does not work on its own.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Computer",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "5",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "39",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… is the area where blocks are kept together to create a script.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Coding Area",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "6",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "40",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………… has various blocks that can be placed into the coding area.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Blocks Palette",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "6",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "41",
        "QUESTION": "A ………………………… block is used to jump.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Hop",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "6",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "42",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the main space where the action takes place in the project.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "6",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "43",
        "QUESTION": "Name the main character that performs actions.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "6",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "44",
        "QUESTION": "Name the sign that is used to start a new project.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "6",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "45",
        "QUESTION": "………………………… can think and act on their own.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Humans",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "7",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "46",
        "QUESTION":
            "A computer is used in …………………………for doing practical work in a lab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Schools",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "7",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "47",
        "QUESTION": "A ………………………… does not have any feelings.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Computer",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "7",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "48",
        "QUESTION": "A computer can do many …………………………… at the same time.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Tasks",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "7",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "49",
        "QUESTION": "A computer cannot store large amount of information.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "7",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "50",
        "QUESTION": "A computer is used in shops to keep records of customers.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "7",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "51",
        "QUESTION": "A computer is used to find information about space.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "7",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "52",
        "QUESTION":
            "A computer does not get tired and can work for long hours.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "7",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "53",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ……………………………………… works on the input to give the output.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CPU",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "54",
        "QUESTION": "A computer follows the ……………………………………… cycle.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "IPO",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "55",
        "QUESTION": "The mouse is an ……………………………………… device.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Input",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "56",
        "QUESTION": "The CPU processes data.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "57",
        "QUESTION": "In the IPO cycle, P stands for program.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "58",
        "QUESTION":
            "The data and instructions that you enter into a computer are\ncalled input.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "59",
        "QUESTION": "CPU",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "60",
        "QUESTION": "IPO",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "61",
        "QUESTION": "Which part of a computer displays the output?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "8",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "62",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ................................... is mainly used for playing video games.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Joystick",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "63",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ................................... is used to select or modify text on a screen.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Mouse",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "64",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ................................... is used to scan documents or images from paper to the computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Scanner",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "65",
        "QUESTION":
            "A monitor is also known as a ................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "VDU",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "66",
        "QUESTION":
            "................................... are worn over the ears.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Headphones",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "67",
        "QUESTION":
            "................................... key is used to give a space between two words.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spacebar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "68",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ................................... is used to record your voice.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Microphone",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "69",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ................................... helps you draw pictures and play games.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Mouse",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "70",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ................................... allows you to listen to music.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Speaker",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "71",
        "QUESTION":
            "A printed copy is called a ................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Hard Copy",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "72",
        "QUESTION":
            "A printer is an ................................... device.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Output",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "73",
        "QUESTION":
            "................................... keys are used to move the cursor up and down.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Arrow",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "74",
        "QUESTION": "A printer shows the work done by you.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "75",
        "QUESTION": "A headset combines a microphone and headphones.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "76",
        "QUESTION": "A touchscreen is an input and output device.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "77",
        "QUESTION": "A mouse helps you draw pictures.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "78",
        "QUESTION": "A smart board is used to listen to music.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "79",
        "QUESTION": "Backspace key is used to erase the letters on the right.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "9",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "80",
        "QUESTION": "A ……………………………………… is used to store a huge amount of data.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Hard Disk",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "81",
        "QUESTION": "The full form of CD is ……………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Compact Disc",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "82",
        "QUESTION": "A pen drive is also known as a ……………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Flash Drive",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "83",
        "QUESTION": "A ……………………………………… is used in mobile phones.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Memory Card",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "84",
        "QUESTION": "Storage devices are used to store ……………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Data",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "85",
        "QUESTION": "A ……………………………………… is fixed inside the CPU cabinet.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Hard Disk",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "86",
        "QUESTION": "A ……………………………………… is used to store HD videos.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Blu-ray Disc",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "87",
        "QUESTION": "The full form of DVD is ……………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Digital Versatile Disc",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "88",
        "QUESTION": "A memory card is round in shape.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "89",
        "QUESTION": "A DVD is an optical disc.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "90",
        "QUESTION": "A CD stores more data than a DVD.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "91",
        "QUESTION": "A computer must have a hard disk.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "92",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the port through which a pen drive is connected to a computer.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "93",
        "QUESTION": "Name a storage device that is smaller than a pen drive",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "10",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "94",
        "QUESTION":
            "The white area where you make colourful drawings is called the ……………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Drawing Area",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "11",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "95",
        "QUESTION": "The ……………………………………… shape is used to draw a curved line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Curve",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "11",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "96",
        "QUESTION": "Color1 is used to choose the ……………………………………… colour.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Line",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "11",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "97",
        "QUESTION": "The Size group is used to change the line size.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "11",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "98",
        "QUESTION": "There are four types of arrows in the Shape group.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "11",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "99",
        "QUESTION": "Color 2 is used to choose the line colour.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "11",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "100",
        "QUESTION":
            "How many styles are there in the Fill option to draw colour-filled shapes?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "11",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "101",
        "QUESTION": "How many times can you modify a curve?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "11",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "102",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ……………………………………… tool is used to draw freehand lines or curves.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Pencil",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "103",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ……………………………………… tool is not a part of the Tools group.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Select",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "104",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Fill with color tool is used to fill colours in ……………………………………… shapes.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Closed",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "105",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ……………………………………… application is used to draw and colour pictures.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Paint",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "106",
        "QUESTION":
            "To add text in the drawing, you can use the ……………………………………… tool.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Text",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "107",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ……………………………………… tool is used to erase a part of the drawing.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Eraser",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "108",
        "QUESTION": "The Pencil tool is used to draw freehand drawings.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "109",
        "QUESTION":
            "While using the Text tool, the pointer changes to ‘J’ shape.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "110",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Fill with color tool is used to select a colour from an existing object.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "12",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "111",
        "QUESTION": "The …………………………… blocks are orange in colour.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Control",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "13",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "112",
        "QUESTION": "The ……………………………… blocks are used to move the sprite.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Motion",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "13",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "113",
        "QUESTION": "The ………………………… block change the look of the sprite.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Looks",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "13",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "114",
        "QUESTION": "How many block categories are there in ScratchJr?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "13",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "115",
        "QUESTION": "What is the colour of the sound blocks?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "13",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "116",
        "QUESTION": "Which blocks are yellow in colour?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "13",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "117",
        "QUESTION":
            "A CPU processes ………………………… and ………………………… given to the computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Data, Instructions",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "118",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………… consists of number keys, arithmetic operators, and the decimal point.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Numeric keypad",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "119",
        "QUESTION":
            "…………………………… keys are used for moving through the documents.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Navigation",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "120",
        "QUESTION":
            "The parts of a computer that can be touched are called ………………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Hardware",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "121",
        "QUESTION": "A computer has four main parts.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "122",
        "QUESTION": "MU stands for Memory Utility.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "123",
        "QUESTION": "A CPU is made up of AU and LU.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "124",
        "QUESTION":
            "The information that you see on a monitor is known as soft copy.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "125",
        "QUESTION":
            "Function keys are placed on the right side of the keyboard.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "126",
        "QUESTION":
            "A computer displays ............................................... after processing the data.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Output",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "127",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................................... monitor consumes least power.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "LED",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "128",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................... keys are either used alone or in combination with other keys to perform certain actions.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Control",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "129",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ............................................... displays all the work that you do on a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Monitor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "14",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "130",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... is the first screen of Windows that appears when the computer is switched on.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Desktop",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "131",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... is the long horizontal bar at the bottom of the desktop.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Taskbar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "132",
        "QUESTION":
            "The right side of the taskbar contains the ............................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Notification Area",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "133",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................... the icons means arranging them in a proper sequence.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Sorting",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "134",
        "QUESTION":
            "To select non-adjacent items, hold down the ............................... key and click on the desired icons.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Ctrl",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "135",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................... acts as a link between the user and the hardware.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Operating System",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "136",
        "QUESTION": "The clock is present on the left side of the taskbar.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "137",
        "QUESTION": "To select an icon, simply click on it.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "138",
        "QUESTION": "Double-clicking on the icon opens the window.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "139",
        "QUESTION":
            "Show desktop button is present on the left side of the taskbar.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "140",
        "QUESTION":
            "To change the desktop background, right-click on the blank area of the desktop.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "141",
        "QUESTION":
            "In a GUI, the user types text-based commands to give instructions to a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "142",
        "QUESTION":
            "The program that manages all the jobs of a computer is called ........................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Operating System",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "143",
        "QUESTION":
            "To arrange the icons on the desktop, ........................................ click on the blank area.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Right",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "144",
        "QUESTION":
            "The button that gives quick access to programs, Windows applications, Help, etc., is known as the ........................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Start Button",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "145",
        "QUESTION":
            "........................................ is an example of an operating system.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Linux",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "146",
        "QUESTION":
            "........................................ are the mini programs that provide easy access to the frequently used tools.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Gadgets",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "15",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "147",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... tool is used to select any part of the picture that you want to change.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Select",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "148",
        "QUESTION":
            "Pencil tool is used to draw free-form lines or ............................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Curves",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "149",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... tool is used to copy the colour from one object to another.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Color Picker",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "150",
        "QUESTION":
            "Paint provides ............................... different types of callout shapes.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Three",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "151",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................... tool is used to draw rectangular or square shapes.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Rectangle",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "152",
        "QUESTION":
            "Once the drawing is made, you cannot make any changes to it.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "153",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can remove the selection box by clicking on the drawing.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "154",
        "QUESTION":
            "Rotate means to turn the selected picture horizontally or vertically.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "155",
        "QUESTION": "Zoom Slider option is available on the Title bar.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "156",
        "QUESTION":
            "Home tab contains commands to resize, rotate, crop, and select picture.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "157",
        "QUESTION":
            "........................................ tool is used to increase or decrease the view size of the objects.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Zoom",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "158",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which command is used to make a duplicate copy of an object?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Copy",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "159",
        "QUESTION":
            "The .................................................. tool is used to select the part of an image in an irregular shape.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Free-form Selection",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "160",
        "QUESTION":
            "The shortcut key to undo command is .................................................. .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Ctrl + Z",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "161",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can increase or decrease the size of the picture using the .................................................. option.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Resize",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "16",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "162",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... is a blank area in the left margin of a document.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Selection Area",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "163",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Word application opens a ............................... document with the temporary name, Document1.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Blank",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "164",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................... option reverses the effect of the last command.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Undo",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "165",
        "QUESTION":
            "Incorrectly spelt words can be seen with a ............................... wavy line under them.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Red",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "166",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... option provides a list of synonyms and antonyms.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Thesaurus",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "167",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can correct the spellings and grammar by clicking on Spelling & Grammar button on the Review tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "168",
        "QUESTION": "Copy and Paste options are used to duplicate the text.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "169",
        "QUESTION": "You can select the Thesaurus option in the File group.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "170",
        "QUESTION":
            "To select a sentence, hold down the Shift key and click anywhere on the sentence.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "171",
        "QUESTION":
            "To select a paragraph, double-click anywhere in the paragraph.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "172",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Word application opens a blank document with the name ........................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Document1",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "173",
        "QUESTION":
            "Grammatical errors are indicated with a ........................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Green wavy line",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "174",
        "QUESTION":
            "The small blinking vertical line on the screen is known as ........................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cursor",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "175",
        "QUESTION":
            "........................................ is a feature of Word that shifts the text to the next line by default if the text does not fit in the current line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Wrapping",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "17",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "176",
        "QUESTION":
            "By default, text is aligned to the ............................... margins.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Left",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "177",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................... is the vertical distance between successive lines of the text.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Line Spacing",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "178",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................... case capitalises the first letter of the selected sentence.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Sentence",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "179",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ............................... is a small graphic symbol that indicates items in a list.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Bullet",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "180",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................................. effect emphasises the text by slanting it to the right.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Italic",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "181",
        "QUESTION":
            "By default, Microsoft Word sets the font to Calibri (Body).",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "182",
        "QUESTION":
            "Justified alignment means that the text is aligned with the left margin.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "183",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can apply bullets to a text document by selecting the Bullets button.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "184",
        "QUESTION": "Formatting effects can be applied using the Insert tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "185",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Bold button is used to display the text in a darker shade than the rest of the text.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "186",
        "QUESTION":
            "........................................ alignment is used to set the text evenly between the left and the right margins.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Justify",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "187",
        "QUESTION":
            "The default line spacing for most Quick Style sets is ........................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Single",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "188",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Font Size box is available on the ........................................ tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Font",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "189",
        "QUESTION": "On which tab is the Font Color button available?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Home",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "190",
        "QUESTION":
            ".................................................. changes the selected text to lowercase.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Lowercase",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "18",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "191",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................... is one of the easiest programming language.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Scratch",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "192",
        "QUESTION":
            "A computer understands only ............................... languages.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Programming",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "193",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ............................... is a graphic character that moves on the stage.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Sprite",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "194",
        "QUESTION":
            "In Scratch, the sprite moves on the ............................... when you run a program.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Stage",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "195",
        "QUESTION":
            "A script is also called a .................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Program",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "196",
        "QUESTION": "The Scripts Area is the place where you create a script.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "197",
        "QUESTION": "A script is a collection of step-wise instructions.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "198",
        "QUESTION": "A script consists of at least two blocks.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "199",
        "QUESTION": "You can turn the sprite only in the clockwise direction.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "200",
        "QUESTION": "You can drag and drop the blocks in the Script Area.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "201",
        "QUESTION":
            "Scratch provides a number of in-built ........................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Sprites",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "202",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ........................................ contains a set of blocks that are used to program the sprite.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Blocks Palette",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "203",
        "QUESTION":
            "Blocks related to the movement of sprite are given in the ........................................ category.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Motion Block",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "204",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can add the ............................................... blocks by clicking on the 'Add Extension' button.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Pen",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "19",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "205",
        "QUESTION":
            "The data which you put into the computer is processed by the ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CPU",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "206",
        "QUESTION": "The processed data is known as  ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Information",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "207",
        "QUESTION":
            "The information in the computer is stored in the form of ………………………… digits, 0’s and 1‘s.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Binary",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "208",
        "QUESTION": "A flash drive is popularly known as …………………………… drive.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Pen",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "209",
        "QUESTION":
            "The information stored in ………………………………… is lost when the power goes off.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "RAM",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "210",
        "QUESTION": "RAM stands for Random Accept Memory.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "211",
        "QUESTION": "1 Megabyte is equal to 1024 Gigabytes.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "212",
        "QUESTION": "A memory card is a storage medium for portable devices.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "213",
        "QUESTION": "External memory stores information for a longer period.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "214",
        "QUESTION":
            "The set of characters, like letters, digits, or special characters\nthat represent facts or figures is known as data.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "215",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................... holds the start up instructions that tell a computer what to do, when it is turned on.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "ROM",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "216",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................... is an optical storage medium and a thin circular disc with a reflective metal coating.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "CD",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "217",
        "QUESTION":
            "Internal memory is also known as ............................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Main memory",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "218",
        "QUESTION":
            "The data stored in the computer memory is measured in ............................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Bytes",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "219",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which storage device has the highest storage capacity among the following?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Hard Disk",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "20",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "220",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………… is a long horizontal bar present at the bottom of the desktop.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Taskbar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "221",
        "QUESTION":
            "The middle section of the taskbar is known as the ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Quick Launch Bar",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "222",
        "QUESTION":
            "Battery status can be seen on the taskbar in the ………………………… area.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Notification",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "223",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… are the graphical images that give a quick access to the related applications.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Application Icons",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "224",
        "QUESTION":
            "To customise the desktop, right-click on the blank area and select the ………………………… option.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Personalize",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "225",
        "QUESTION":
            "Quick Launch Bar is present between the Start button and the\nNotification Area.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "226",
        "QUESTION": "You cannot customise the taskbar to best suit your needs.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "227",
        "QUESTION": "Speaker icon is present on the Quick Launch Bar.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "228",
        "QUESTION":
            "Notification Area provides an easy and quick way to open\nthe programs.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "229",
        "QUESTION":
            "The options present in the Start menu provide access to the main programs on the computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "230",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which folder holds the deleted files/folders in a computer?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Recycle Bin",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "231",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................ is a new feature that takes you straight to the documents, pictures, songs, or websites you have recently visited.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Jump Lists",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "232",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................................ option arranges all the open windows from the top left corner of the screen to the bottom right in layers.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cascading windows",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "233",
        "QUESTION":
            "While customising the desktop,the ........................................... option makes the windows glass borders, Start menu, and taskbar transparent.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Enable transparency",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "234",
        "QUESTION":
            "The full form of GUI is ............................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Graphical User Interface",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "21",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "235",
        "QUESTION":
            "A smart refrigerator is connected to the internet and can be controlled by a .................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Smartphone",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "236",
        "QUESTION":
            "IoT-enabled devices can share the data through the .................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Internet",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "237",
        "QUESTION":
            "Some IoT-devices contain .................................... that scan their environment for any significant changes.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "sensors",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "238",
        "QUESTION": ".................................... makes things smart.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "AI",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "239",
        "QUESTION":
            "A smart .................................... can record your heart rate, oxygen level, footsteps, etc.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "watch",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "240",
        "QUESTION":
            "Giving weather information is not a feature of a smart watch.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "241",
        "QUESTION":
            "The term 'Internet of Things' was first coined by Kevin Ashton in 1999.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "242",
        "QUESTION": "Most smart cars run on fuel.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "243",
        "QUESTION":
            "Using IoT, you can manage different agricultural resources.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "244",
        "QUESTION":
            "A smart TV suggests your favourite shows, movies, etc., based on your preferences.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "245",
        "QUESTION":
            "Self-driving cars are automobiles that can drive without human involvement by sensing their ............................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Environment",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "246",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which among the following is not a feature of a smart watch?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Surveillance cameras",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "247",
        "QUESTION":
            "A smart camera protects your home by ......................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Both a and b",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "248",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................ is the interlinking of digital devices, people, appliances, etc., with one another to share information and data through the internet.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "IoT",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "249",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which among the following devices is a voice-controllable speaker?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Amazon Echo",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "250",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ............................................ is a small computing device that is worn on the wrist.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Smart Watch",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "22",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "251",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… refer to the amount of blank space between the edge of the page and the document text.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Margins",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "252",
        "QUESTION":
            "To copy the formatting effect to multiple sections of text, ………………………… on the Format Painter button.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Double-click",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "253",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................................. is used to place some information on the top of every page.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Header",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "254",
        "QUESTION":
            "The default margins are set at ………………………… from top, bottom, left, and right edge of the page.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "1 inch",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "255",
        "QUESTION": "By default, tab stops are set at every ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "0.5 inch",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "256",
        "QUESTION":
            "Indentation determines the amount of spacing above or below a paragraph.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "257",
        "QUESTION":
            "Tab key is used to move the cursor forward certain spaces in a document.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "258",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Page Break option splits the document into two or more columns.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "259",
        "QUESTION": "Landscape is the default paper orientation in Word 2010.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "260",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Subscript option places the selected text slightly above the baseline.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "261",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................................ property sets the printing direction of the text.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Page Orientation",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "262",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................ allows you to insert a break in the page and move the cursor to a new page.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Page Break",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "263",
        "QUESTION":
            "The selected text can be shifted 1/2 inch away from the left margin by using the ............................................ button.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Increase indent",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "264",
        "QUESTION":
            "The top and bottom margins of a document can be changed by using the ........................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Vertical ruler",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "265",
        "QUESTION":
            "In ............................................ orientation, the document is printed width-wise.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Landscape",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "23",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "266",
        "QUESTION":
            "If you click on the ………………………… check box, it will search the text with the similar case that you have typed in the Find what text box.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Match case",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "267",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… is a gallery of pre-designed pictures that can be inserted directly in a document.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Clip Art",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "268",
        "QUESTION":
            "Lines, Basic Shapes, and Block Arrows are the options of ………………………… button.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Shapes",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "269",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………… feature is used to create special text effects.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "WordArt",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "270",
        "QUESTION": "Shapes can be inserted from the ………………………… group.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Illustrations",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "25",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "271",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Replace button can replace the searched text with the new text, at once.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "272",
        "QUESTION": "The Shift key is used to cancel the search.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "273",
        "QUESTION": "The Picture option is present on the Home tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "274",
        "QUESTION": "You cannot insert text in a Shape.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "275",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Shift key is pressed to maintain the height and width ratio of a shape.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "276",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which shortcut key is used to open the Navigation pane to find the text?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Ctrl + F",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "277",
        "QUESTION":
            "When you insert a shape in a document, a new tab named ............................................ appears under the Drawing Tools.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Format",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "278",
        "QUESTION":
            "The WordArt button is present on the ............................................ tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Insert",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "279",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which among the following shortcut keys is used to open the Find and Replace dialog box?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Ctrl + H",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "280",
        "QUESTION":
            "The border button is found in the ............................................................. group.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Paragraph",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "24",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "281",
        "QUESTION":
            "When you start a new Scratch project, it begins with a ............................... sprite.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cat",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "282",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... block allows the sprite to say something in a speech bubble.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "say ( )",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "283",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... button is used to end a loop.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Stop",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "284",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... block allows the sprite to wait for a specified number of seconds.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "wait ( ) secs",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "285",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................... block will play a specified sound, pausing the script until the sound has finished playing.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "play sound ( ) until done",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "286",
        "QUESTION": "You can make a sprite say something in a speech bubble.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "287",
        "QUESTION": "You cannot change the costume of the sprite.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "288",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Sound blocks are used to play sounds in the Scratch project.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "289",
        "QUESTION": "The Stop button is of green colour.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "290",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can repeat the actions of a sprite as many times as needed.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "291",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the block that allows the sprite to change the costume.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "292",
        "QUESTION": "Which block allows the sprite to say something?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "293",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the button that you use to choose the sprite’s costume.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "294",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the block that makes the sprite wait for a few seconds.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "295",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the block that is used to run the script again and again.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "296",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ........................................ blocks are used to control the looks of a sprite.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Looks",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "297",
        "QUESTION":
            "Click on the ........................................ tab to see and edit the Sprite’s costume.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Costumes",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "298",
        "QUESTION":
            "The say hello block allows the sprite to say something in a speech ........................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Bubble",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "299",
        "QUESTION":
            "To move a block of commands anywhere in the Scripts Area, click on the ........................................ block of the script.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Top",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "26",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "300",
        "QUESTION":
            "When the computer networks are joined together, they form a bigger network called the ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Internet",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "301",
        "QUESTION":
            "Each website is identified by its unique address, known as the ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "URL",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "302",
        "QUESTION":
            "An ………………………… is a company, which offers the use of the internet in exchange for a fee.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "ISP",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "303",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ………………………… is a software that searches various web pages on the World Wide Web for a particular information.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Search Engine",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "304",
        "QUESTION":
            "The act of searching on the World Wide Web by following one link after another, without a planned search strategy, is called ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Net Surfing",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "305",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ………………………… is a digital page of a website that may contain text, images, videos, audio, etc.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Web page",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "306",
        "QUESTION": "WWW refers to a network of websites on the internet.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "307",
        "QUESTION":
            "The URL of any website is entered in the Title bar of a web browser.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "308",
        "QUESTION": "Bing is an example of a search engine.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "309",
        "QUESTION":
            "A modem allows a computer to send or receive information through telephone lines.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "310",
        "QUESTION": "ISP stands for Internet Service Protection.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "311",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ............................................................. is the first page of a website.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Home Page",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "312",
        "QUESTION": "Which of the following is not a search engine?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Google Chrome",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "313",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................ is a software application or program that allows you to access the entire information available on the web.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Web Browser",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "314",
        "QUESTION":
            "When you move the cursor over a link, the cursor changes to a ............................................ shaped pointer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Hand",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "315",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which among the following is an example of a search engine?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Google",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "316",
        "QUESTION":
            "In Google Chrome, ............................................ option displays a list of recently visited websites.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "History",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "27",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "317",
        "QUESTION": "………………………… and ………………………… are two types of software.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Application, System",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "318",
        "QUESTION":
            "An  ………………………… is a language processor that translates the program line by line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Interpreter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "319",
        "QUESTION":
            "An ...................................... controls the overall activities of a computer.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Operating System",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "320",
        "QUESTION":
            "…………………………… programs perform specific tasks related to managing a computer, its devices, or its programs.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Utility",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "321",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………………… software helps you to create and display slides on a computer or a projector.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Presentation",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "322",
        "QUESTION":
            "Application software can run without the presence of system software.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "323",
        "QUESTION":
            "A language processor translates the machine language into programming language.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "324",
        "QUESTION": "Backup is a process of shrinking the files on a disk.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "325",
        "QUESTION": "VisiCalc was the first computer spreadsheet program.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "326",
        "QUESTION":
            "An compiler translates the whole program into an equivalent code in one go.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "327",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which among the following utilities checks the connectivity and configuration of network devices?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Network",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "328",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ..................................................... translates the program code line by line.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Interpreter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "329",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ............................................ program helps you to perform calculations and analyse data in a better way.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Spreadsheet",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "330",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................... is an example of antivirus software.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Norton",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "331",
        "QUESTION":
            "Software designed to meet the specific needs of users are called ............................................... application software.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Special purpose",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "28",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "332",
        "QUESTION":
            "Moving a file/folder means shifting it from its  ………………………… to another location.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Source",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "333",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… is an application that provides detailed information about files, folders, and drives.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Windows Explorer",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "334",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can find a file/folder by typing the keyword in the ………………………… at the top of every window.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Search Box",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "335",
        "QUESTION": "Deleted files can be restored from the ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Recycle Bin",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "336",
        "QUESTION":
            "…………………….........……… button is found at the right edge of the taskbar.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Show Desktop",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "337",
        "QUESTION":
            "To select a consecutive group of files, click on the Ctrl key.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "338",
        "QUESTION":
            "Shift + Del key combination deletes a file/folder permanently.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "339",
        "QUESTION": "In Windows 7, you can display only two windows at a time.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "340",
        "QUESTION":
            "Shake will minimise all open windows except the one you are working with.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "341",
        "QUESTION":
            "To activate the Aero flip 3D feature, press the Windows + Alt keys.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "342",
        "QUESTION":
            "To copy multiple non-adjacent files and folders, press and hold down the ............................................... key.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Ctrl",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "343",
        "QUESTION":
            "..................................... is a faster method to resize an open window.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Snap",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "344",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which among the following offers the most direct way to locate a file?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Search Box",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "345",
        "QUESTION":
            "........................................ allows you to turn the open windows transparent and makes the desktop visible.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Aero Peek",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "346",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ...................................................... feature enables you to preview all open windows as a stack.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Aero Flip 3D",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "29",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "347",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… make use of AI to update a commuter about traffic congestions in a particular area and the estimated time to reach a particular destination.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Google Maps",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "348",
        "QUESTION":
            "AI is capable of understanding human language with the help of a concept called ………………………… .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Natural Language Processing",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "349",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… is a field that deals with the idea of computers replicating human vision.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Computer Vision",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "350",
        "QUESTION":
            "AI-based apps use a highly accurate ………………………… for processing data.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Algorithm",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "351",
        "QUESTION":
            "In Gmail, AI is only used for scanning an email for viruses.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "352",
        "QUESTION":
            "Alexa is a device that makes use of NLP to interpret voice commands.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "353",
        "QUESTION": "Like humans, AI cannot take independent decisions.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "354",
        "QUESTION":
            "Computer Vision is a field that deals with the processing of language.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "355",
        "QUESTION":
            "Google Maps make use of AI to update about traffic congestion.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "30",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "356",
        "QUESTION":
            "A presentation is a collection of ………………………… that are arranged in a sequential manner.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Slides",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "357",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can select different slide layouts from the ………………………… button.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Layout",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "358",
        "QUESTION":
            "When a file is saved in PowerPoint, it creates ………………………… extension.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": ".pptx",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "359",
        "QUESTION":
            "The ………………………… view displays a miniature view of all the slides in a presentation.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Slide Sorter",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "360",
        "QUESTION":
            "In Microsoft PowerPoint 2010, the ………………………… view is the default presentation view.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Normal",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "361",
        "QUESTION":
            "Clip Art button is present on the ............................................... tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Insert",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "362",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................... function key is used to display the Slide Show.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "F5",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "363",
        "QUESTION": "In which view do you get the Outline tab?",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Normal View",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "364",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ............................................... is like a page in a presentation.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Slide",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "365",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ............................................... displays the slide in full screen mode.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Slide Show",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "366",
        "QUESTION":
            "The shortcut key to save a presentation is ............................................................... .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Ctrl + S",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "367",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the boxes with dotted borders that are part of the most slide layouts.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "368",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which tool is used to present data or information visually in the form of graphics, like pyramids, charts, etc?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "369",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the option that is used to create additional notes for the current slide.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "370",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which feature of PowerPoint includes a sample slide show containing various themes and layouts?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "31",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "371",
        "QUESTION":
            "........................................ refers to the way things are arranged on a slide.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Slide Layout",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "372",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can add shapes by selecting the Shapes button in the Illustrations group on the ………………………… tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Insert",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "373",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… is a placeholder where one can enter and manipulate the text.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Text Box",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "374",
        "QUESTION": "………………………… feature helps us to create decorative text.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "WordArt",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "375",
        "QUESTION":
            "To rotate a shape object or clipart, click on the ………………………… handle.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Rotation",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "376",
        "QUESTION":
            "The layout of a slide can only be modified in the Slide Sorter View.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "377",
        "QUESTION":
            "Ctrl + P key combination is used to print the slides of a presentation.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "378",
        "QUESTION":
            "In the Normal View, the vertical bar indicates the new location of a slide.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "379",
        "QUESTION": "Shadow option is present on the Home tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "380",
        "QUESTION": "Text box does not appear in the Outline tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "381",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Slide Sorter View button is present on the  ............................................... tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "View",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "382",
        "QUESTION":
            "The WordArt button is present on the ............................................... tab.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Insert",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "383",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................... tab contains the Text Box tool.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Insert",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "384",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................... button on the Format tab is used to apply 3-D rotation to a shape.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Shape Effects",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "385",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................... stretches or shrinks the dimension of an object.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Resizing",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "386",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Slides tab and Outline tab are available under which view?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "387",
        "QUESTION":
            "Name the button which displays options like Lines, Rectangles, Flowchart, etc.",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "388",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which key helps you to select more than one shape at a time?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "389",
        "QUESTION":
            "Which option is used to create a mirror image of the selected shape or object?",
        "TYPE": "B",
        "CHAPTERID": "32",
        "CATEGORYID": "2",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "390",
        "QUESTION":
            "Music blocks can be added by clicking on the ....................................... button.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Add Extension",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "391",
        "QUESTION":
            "The .............................................. is represented by x : 0 and y : 0 coordinates.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Origin",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "392",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… is the place where you pick and drop the blocks to create a script.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Scripts Area",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "393",
        "QUESTION":
            "You can add a new sprite by clicking on the ………………………… button.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Choose a Sprite",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "394",
        "QUESTION":
            "Music can be added to a Scratch project by using the blocks available in the ………………………… blocks palette.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Music",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "395",
        "QUESTION": "The name of a sprite cannot be changed.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "396",
        "QUESTION":
            "Stage is the main working area where the sprite moves and performs actions.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "397",
        "QUESTION": "You can draw a new sprite in the paint editor.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "398",
        "QUESTION": "The script area is also known as coding area.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "399",
        "QUESTION":
            "The Full Screen control is present on the top-right corner of the stage.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "400",
        "QUESTION":
            "............................................ is the place where sprites move and interact with each other.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Stage",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "401",
        "QUESTION":
            "The collection of step-wise instructions given to a sprite is known as a ............................................ .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Script",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "402",
        "QUESTION":
            "To add the music blocks to your Scratch project, click on the ............................................ button first.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Add Extension",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "403",
        "QUESTION":
            "The set rotation style block is present in the ............................................ blocks palette.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Motion",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "33",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "404",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… allows users to send instant messages back and forth to each other.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Online Chat",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "405",
        "QUESTION":
            "................................... refers to learning with the use of technology that enables people to learn anytime and anywhere.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "E-learning",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "406",
        "QUESTION":
            "A ………………………… means to communicate by exchanging video and audio at the same time.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Video Conference",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "407",
        "QUESTION":
            "To write an e-mail, one has to click on the ………………………… option.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Compose",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "408",
        "QUESTION":
            "………………………… can be defined as a medium of delivering television content over an internet connection.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Internet TV",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "1",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "409",
        "QUESTION":
            "A username is a unique name that identifies a website on the web.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "410",
        "QUESTION": "No two individuals can have the same email address.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "411",
        "QUESTION": "Bcc stands for Blue Carbon Copy.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "412",
        "QUESTION": "A file larger than 25MB cannot be sent as an attachment.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "True",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "413",
        "QUESTION":
            "E-learning is more expensive as compared to traditional ways of learning.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "False",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "4",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "414",
        "QUESTION":
            "E-mail addresses mentioned in ............................................... field are visible to all the recipients of the mail.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Cc",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "415",
        "QUESTION":
            "Social networking sites are also called .................................. .",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Social Media",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "416",
        "QUESTION":
            "The user name and the domain name parts of an e-mail address are separated by the ............................................... symbol.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "@",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      },
      {
        "ID": "417",
        "QUESTION":
            "An e-mail attachment is indicated with a ............................................... icon.",
        "RIGHTANSWER": "Paper clip",
        "TYPE": "R",
        "CHAPTERID": "34",
        "CATEGORYID": "5",
        "ABBREVIATION_TIME": "0"
      }
    ],
    "CLASS": [
      {"ID": "1", "NAME": "Class-1"},
      {"ID": "2", "NAME": "Class-2"},
      {"ID": "3", "NAME": "Class-3"},
      {"ID": "4", "NAME": "Class-4"},
      {"ID": "5", "NAME": "Class-5"}
    ]
  }
};
